<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<research title="Selected Measures and Research Methods" description="This tool helps you identify suitable research methods and standardized ways to operationalize concepts for your HCI study. It offers introductory guidance for a quick start, but it is not a substitute for thorough literature research or feedback from your supervisor. An online repository for scientific instruments can also be found at: zis.gesis.org">
	<options type="dropdown" id="types" question="What is the purpose of your study?">
		<option id="formative" next="designdecision">Designing or improving a system, interaction, or method (Formative Evaluation)</option>
		<option id="summative" next="evidences">Testing and understanding a system or people (Summative Evaluation)</option>
		<option id="literature" next="literaturereviews">Reviewing and summarizing scientific literature (Secondary Research)</option>
	</options>
	<options type="dropdown" id="literaturereviews" question="Why do you want to read the literature?">
		<option id="narrative">Finding research streams, frameworks, gaps, inconsistencies (Traditional Reviews)</option>
		<option id="systematic">Answer one specific research question (Systematic Reviews)</option>
		<option id="scoping">Identifying research scope and answer a general research question (Scoping Reviews)</option>
		<option id="metaanalysis">Summarizing results of empirical studies addressing the same question (Meta-Analysis)</option>
	</options>
	<options type="dropdown" id="designdecision" question="What is the current stage of your design process?">
		<option id="solutions" next="prototyping">Start the design from scratch (Solution-oriented)</option>
		<option id="problems" next="evidences">Identify the problems with something that exists (Problem-oriented)</option>
	</options>
	<options type="dropdown" id="prototyping" question="Are you interested in the design process or outcome?">
		<option id="designprocess">Interested in the design process or design space (Design Method)</option>
		<option id="prototype">Interested in the final outcome (Prototyping)</option>
	</options>
	<options type="dropdown" id="evidences" question="What scientific evidence is your research based on?">
		<option id="analytical" next="analyticaldecisions">Based on analysis and logic (Analytical Evidence)</option>
		<option id="empirical" next="sample">Based on experience by observation (Empirical Evidence)</option>
	</options>
	<options type="dropdown" id="sample" question="On what basis would you like to draw your sample?">
		<option id="single" notIf="summative">A single case (one person, one event, one location, one organization, ...)</option>
		<option id="experts" notIf="summative">A special subset (selected experts, designers, events, locations...)</option>
		<option id="randomsample" notIf="formative" next="method">A random/representative sample from a population (people, groups, events, locations,...)</option>
	</options>
	<options type="dropdown" id="analyticaldecisions" question="On what is your analysis based on?">
		<option id="datadriven" next="concept">Data (data-driven)</option>
		<option id="modeldriven">Models (model-driven)</option>
	</options>
	<options type="checkbox" id="method" question="How do you draw your sample?">
		<option id="quantitative" next="datadecision">Measuring numerical values (Quantitative Methods)</option>
		<option id="qualitative" next="datadecision">Collecting non-numeric feedback (Qualitative Methods)</option>
	</options>
	<options type="checkbox" id="datadecision" question="Where does your data come from?">
		<option id="objective" onlyIf="quantitative" next="concept">From a measuring instrument (Objective data)</option>
		<option id="subjective"  onlyIf="quantitative" next="concept">From a statement of a person (Subjective data)</option>
	</options>
	<options type="checkbox" id="concept" question="Which concepts do you want to measure?">
		<option id="demographics" alwaysOn="on" disabled="on">Demographics (required)</option>
		<option id="attention" onlyIf="objective">Attention</option>
		<option id="accessibility" onlyIf="objective">Accessibility</option>
		<option id="awareness">Awareness</option>
		<option id="biases" onlyIf="objective">Bias</option>
		<option id="bodyownership" onlyIf="subjective">Body Ownership</option>
		<option id="collaboration">Collaboration</option>
		<option id="emotions" onlyIf="subjective">Emotions</option>
		<option id="empathy" onlyIf="subjective">Empathy</option>
		<option id="explainability" onlyIf="subjective">Explainability</option>
		<option id="ergonomics">Ergonomics</option>
		<option id="fitness">Fitness</option>
		<option id="flow" onlyIf="subjective">Flow</option>
		<option id="hedonicpragmatic" onlyIf="subjective">Fun</option>
		<option id="games" onlyIf="subjective">Gaming Experience</option>
		<option id="health" onlyIf="subjective">Health</option>
		<option id="humanlikeness" onlyIf="subjective">Human-Likeness</option>
		<option id="immersion" onlyIf="subjective">Immersion</option>
		<option id="learning" onlyIf="objective">Learning</option>
		<option id="longitudinal" onlyIf="subjective">Longitudinal Experience</option>
		<option id="memory" onlyIf="objective">Memory</option>
		<option id="mindfulness" onlyIf="subjective">Mindfulness</option>
		<option id="motivation" onlyIf="subjective">Motivation</option>
		<option id="movement" onlyIf="objective">Movement</option>
		<option id="performance" onlyIf="objective">Performance</option>
		<option id="personality" onlyIf="subjective">Personality</option>
		<option id="presence" onlyIf="subjective">Presence</option>
		<option id="satisfaction" onlyIf="subjective">Satisfaction</option>
		<option id="selfesteem" onlyIf="subjective">Self-Esteem</option>
		<option id="selfefficacy" onlyIf="subjective">Self-Efficacy</option>
		<option id="sensualacuity">Sensual Acuity</option>
		<option id="stress">Stress/Excitement/Relaxation</option>  
		<option id="socialacceptance" onlyIf="subjective">Social Acceptance</option>
		<option id="textanalysis" onlyIf="objective">Text Metrics</option>
		<option id="trust" onlyIf="subjective">Trust</option>
		<option id="usability" onlyIf="subjective">Usability</option>
		<option id="userexperience" onlyIf="subjective">User Experience</option> 
		<option id="workload" onlyIf="subjective">Cognitive Load</option>
	</options>
	<measures>
		<method id="demographics" category="summative,demographics" title="Demographics (required)">
			<p>Always record for each individual participating in your study:</p>
			<div class="list-group">
				<div class="list-group-item"><div><div class="fw-bold">Gender</div> <div>Options: male, female, other, do not want to specify</div></div></div>
				<div class="list-group-item"><div><div class="fw-bold">Age</div><div>Options: numerical input from 0 to N</div></div></div>
				<div class="list-group-item"><div><div class="fw-bold">Highest Academic Degree</div><div>Options: none, primary school, secondary school, post-secondary school diploma / high school diploma, completed vocational training, completed university studies, doctoral degree</div></div></div>
				<div class="list-group-item"><div><div class="fw-bold">Occupation</div><div>Options: Management, Natural Sciences, Engineering, Health, Law and Order, Clerical, Spiritual, Social, Humanities, Services and Sales, Agriculture and Food, Craft, Military, Others</div></div></div>
				<div class="list-group-item"><div><div class="fw-bold">Nationality</div><div>Options: <a href="country.txt">Get full list</a></div></div></div>
			</div>
			<p class="mt-2">More participant-related information could be: </p>
			<div class="list-group">
				<div class="list-group-item"><div><div class="fw-bold">Expertise</div><div>What is special about your participants (experts in their field? students? ...)</div></div></div>
				<div class="list-group-item"><div><div class="fw-bold">Trial Time</div><div>Experimental trial time for each participant</div></div></div>
				<div class="list-group-item"><div><div class="fw-bold">Compensation</div><div>€, credit points for the lecture</div></div></div>
				<div class="list-group-item"><div><div class="fw-bold">Health Limitations or Impairments</div><div>Only if relevant to your study context...</div></div></div>
				<div class="list-group-item"><div><div class="fw-bold">Ethnic, Cultural, or Racial Background</div><div>Only when this is important for your study...</div></div></div>
			</div>
		</method>

		<method id="skinconductance" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,stress" title="Quantitative Objective Stress: Skin Conductance Response (SCR)/Electro Dermal Activity (EDA)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Skin Conductance Response (SCR) is a measure of the electrical conductance of the skin. It is used as an indicator of sympathetic nervous system activity, which is related to emotional or physiological arousal. SCR is typically measured by attaching electrodes to the skin, usually on the fingers or palms, and recording the electrical conductance between them. The electrodes are connected to a device that amplifies and records the electrical signals.  </p><p>The resulting data can then be analyzed to determine the level of SCR, which can be used to infer changes in emotional or physiological arousal in response to various stimuli. SCR is commonly used in research on emotion, cognition, and stress, as well as in clinical applications such as lie detection and biofeedback.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electrodermal_activity" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="heartratevariablity" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,stress" title="Quantitative Objective Stress: Heart Rate Variability (HRV)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Heart Rate Variability (HRV) is a measure of the variation in the time interval between successive heartbeats. It is typically measured by recording the electrocardiogram (ECG) signal, which is the electrical activity of the heart. HRV reflects the balance between the sympathetic and parasympathetic nervous systems, which control the heart rate. A high HRV indicates a healthy balance between the two systems, while a low HRV indicates an imbalance, which may be associated with stress, anxiety, or other health conditions.</p><p>HRV analysis can be used to assess the overall health of the cardiovascular system, as well as to monitor the effects of interventions such as exercise, medication, or stress management. It is also used in research on physiological regulation, psychophysiology, and health care.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heart_rate_variability" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p> 
		</method>

		<method id="jnd" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,sensualacuity" title="Quantitative Objective Sensual Acuity: Just-Noticeable Difference (JND)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Just-Noticeable Difference (JND) is a concept in psychophysics that refers to the minimum amount of change in a stimulus that is needed for it to be perceived as different from the original stimulus. It is the smallest difference in the intensity, duration, or other physical characteristics of a stimulus that can be detected by the observer. The JND is determined by the characteristics of the observer and the properties of the stimulus. For example, the JND for a visual stimulus is dependent on the properties of the observer's eyes, the lighting conditions, and the characteristics of the stimulus.</p><p>JND is used in many fields such as product design, marketing, and human-computer interaction to understand how small changes in a product or design can be perceived by users. It also has a great importance in research on sensation and perception as it allows to quantify the sensitivity of the human senses.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Just-noticeable_difference" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p> 
		</method>

		<method id="borg" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,fitness" title="Quantitative Subjective Fitness: Rating of Perceived Exertion (RPE) / 'Borg Scale'">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Rating of Perceived Exertion (RPE) is a scale used to measure an individual's subjective feeling of effort or exertion during physical activity. It is a simple and reliable tool that allows individuals to rate their effort on a scale of 0 to 20 or 0 to 10, with higher numbers indicating a greater feeling of exertion. The most commonly used RPE scale is the Borg Scale, which ranges from 6 to 20. It is based on the individual's perception of how hard they are working and how much effort they are putting in.</p><p>RPE can be used to monitor exercise intensity, track changes in fitness, and evaluate the effectiveness of exercise programs. It is a simple, non-invasive, and widely used method in exercise physiology, sports science, and rehabilitation. RPE is also used in research on exercise and physical activity, as well as in clinical settings to monitor patients with chronic conditions such as heart disease and diabetes.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rating_of_perceived_exertion" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>  
		</method>

		<method id="gripstrength" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,fitness" title="Quantitative Objective Fitness: Grip Strength (GS)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Grip Strength (GS) is a measure of the maximal force that an individual can exert with their hand or hand-held device. It is typically measured using a hand-held dynamometer, which is a device that measures force when an individual squeezes it with their hand. GS is a widely used measure of upper body strength and it is a simple, reliable and valid measure of muscle function. It is often used to assess the muscle strength of the hand, wrist, and forearm.</p><p>It has been used in many fields such as rehabilitation, sports science, geriatrics, and occupational therapy. It is also used as a predictor of overall health and functional ability, as well as to monitor the effectiveness of exercise and physical therapy programs. In research, it is used to investigate the effects of aging, disease, injury, and other factors on muscle function.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grip_strength" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>   
		</method>

		<method id="heartrate" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,stress" title="Quantitative Objective Stress: Heart Rate (HR)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Heart Rate (HR) is used as a measure of physiological and emotional responses of users interacting with digital devices. HR is widely used as an indicator of emotional and cognitive states, such as stress, excitement, and mental or physical workload. By measuring the HR, researchers can gain insight into how users respond to different interfaces, designs, or features of a digital device, such as mobile phones, tablets, and computers.</p><p>In HCI research, HR measurements can be used in combination with other physiological measurements such as skin conductance, galvanic skin response, and electromyography. This allows researchers to gain a more comprehensive understanding of the user's physiological and emotional responses to different digital devices and interfaces. HR can also be used to evaluate the effectiveness of interventions such as stress management, biofeedback or mindfulness training programs.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heart_rate" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="usabilitytest" category="empirical,problems,randomsample" title="Qualitative Feedback: Usability test with users">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>A usability test is a method used to evaluate the usability of a digital product or system by testing it with users. The goal of a usability test is to identify any problems or issues that users may encounter when using the product or system, and to gather feedback on its overall usability. During a usability test, participants are asked to perform a set of tasks while interacting with the product or system being tested. These tasks are designed to simulate real-world scenarios and are chosen to represent the most important and common activities that users will perform.</p><p>The participants are typically asked to think aloud as they complete the tasks, so that the researchers can understand their thought process and any difficulties they encounter. The usability test is typically conducted in a controlled environment, such as a lab, where the participants' interactions with the product or system can be observed and recorded.</p><p>The test is usually conducted with a small number of participants, usually between 5 to 8, and can be conducted in-person or remotely. The results of the usability test are analyzed to identify any problems or issues that users encountered, and to gather feedback on the overall usability of the product or system. Based on the results, design recommendations can be made to improve the usability of the product or system.</p> 
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Usability_testing" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="publicstats" category="analytical,datadriven" title="Data-driven Analysis: Official/Public Statistics">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Data-driven analysis is a method of using statistical and computational techniques to extract insights and knowledge from data. Official statistics, also known as public statistics, refer to data that is collected and published by government agencies or other official sources. These sources include national statistical agencies, central banks, and other government departments. Official statistics are used in various fields such as economics, social sciences, and public policy. They are considered to be reliable and unbiased, as they are collected and published by neutral and independent organizations.</p><p>In Data-driven Analysis, Official statistics are used as a primary source of data in many research projects and studies. They provide a wealth of information on a wide range of topics such as population, income, education, crime, health, and more. This data can be used to analyze trends, patterns, and relationships between different variables, and to make predictions about future developments.</p><p>In addition to being a valuable source of data, official statistics are also used to validate and benchmark results obtained from other data sources, such as surveys and experiments. For example, official statistics on GDP can be used to validate results from a survey on consumer spending, or official statistics on crime can be used to validate results from an experiment on the effectiveness of a new policing strategy.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Official_statistics" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="ethnography" category="analytical,datadriven" title="Data-driven Analysis: Ethnography/Autoethnography">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Ethnography and Autoethnography are research methods that are used in the field of Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) to understand the cultural and social aspects of technology use.</p><p>Ethnography in HCI involves observing and studying the ways in which people use technology in their everyday lives. It typically involves conducting fieldwork, such as visiting people in their homes or workplaces, to observe how they interact with technology and understand the context in which technology is used. Ethnography in HCI can provide valuable insights into how technology is integrated into people's lives, and how it shapes their social interactions and behaviors.</p><p>Autoethnography is a variation of ethnography that involves the researcher being a part of the culture or community being studied. In HCI, Autoethnography can be used to examine the researcher's own experiences and understanding of technology use. It allows the researcher to explore their own relationship with technology, and to reflect on how it shapes their own behaviors and interactions. Autoethnography allows researcher to understand the personal experience with the technology which can't be captured by traditional ethnography methods.</p><p>Both ethnography and autoethnography are useful methods for understanding the social and cultural dimensions of technology use in HCI. They can provide insights into how technology is integrated into people's lives, how it shapes their behaviors and interactions, and how it is perceived and experienced by different groups of people.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethnography" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="diary" category="empirical,qualitative,subjective,longitudinal" title="Qualitative Feedback: Diary Study with Experience Sampling Method (ESM)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Diary studies are a research method used in Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) to study people's experiences and behaviors over time. Diary studies involve asking participants to document their thoughts, feelings, and activities in a diary, journal, or other form of written record over a period of time, typically days or weeks..</p><p>In HCI, diary studies are used to understand people's everyday experiences with technology, such as how they use it, what problems they encounter, and how it impacts their lives. They can provide insights into how technology is integrated into people's daily routines, how it shapes their behaviors, and how it affects their emotions and well-being.</p><p>Diary studies can be used in a variety of settings, such as in the workplace, at home, or in educational settings. They can be used to study a wide range of technology-related topics, such as mobile phone use, social media, and internet usage..</p><p>Participants are usually asked to complete the diary entries at regular intervals, such as at the end of each day. Participants are also usually asked to complete a final survey or interview to provide more detailed information about their experiences. The diary entries and final survey/interview data can be analyzed together to gain a more complete understanding of the participants' experiences..</p><p>Diary studies are a valuable method in HCI research, as they provide rich and detailed data about people's everyday experiences with technology. They can provide insights that are difficult to obtain through other methods, such as surveys or interviews, and can be particularly useful for understanding how technology is used in naturalistic settings.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://www.nngroup.com/articles/diary-studies/" target="_blank">Nielsen Norman Group</a></p> 
		</method>

		<method id="scnearioofuse" category="empirical,single" title="Qualitative Investigation: Scenario of Use / Case Study / Use Case Study">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>All three methods, Scenario of Use, Case Study and Use Case Study, are similar approaches used to understand how people interact with technology in very specific contexts, and to inform the design and evaluation of technology. They provide detailed and in-depth insights into how people use technology in their everyday lives and help to identify potential issues and areas for improvement.</p><p>A Scenario of Use is a description of a specific situation or context in which a product or system is used. It describes the goals, actions, and interactions of the user, as well as the context in which the product or system is used. Scenarios of use are used to inform the design of a product or system, and to evaluate its usability and effectiveness.</p>  <p>A Case Study is a research method that involves in-depth examination of a specific instance or example of a phenomenon. In HCI, case studies are used to understand the specific experiences and behaviors of individuals or groups in relation to a particular technology or system. They typically involve collecting a variety of data, such as interviews, observations, and documentation, and analyzing it to gain a detailed understanding of the case.</p>  <p>A Use Case Study is a specific type of case study that focuses on the use of a particular product or system. It involves studying how people use a product or system in real-world settings, and understanding the tasks, goals, and interactions that are associated with its use. Use case studies are used to evaluate the usability and effectiveness of a product or system, and to identify potential design improvements.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://www.nngroup.com/articles/quantifying-case-study/" target="_blank">Nielsen Norman Group</a></p>			
		</method>

		<method id="postinterview" category="empirical,qualitative,subjective,randomsample" title="Qualitative Feedback: Semi-Structured Interview">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>A Semi-Structured Interview is a research method used in Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) to gather qualitative data about people's experiences, attitudes, and behaviors in relation to technology. It is a type of interview that combines the flexibility of an unstructured interview with the structure of a structured interview.</p><p>In a semi-structured interview, the interviewer has a set of predetermined questions or topics to guide the conversation, but also allows the interviewee to elaborate on their answers and to introduce new topics. This allows the interviewee to provide in-depth and detailed responses, while still ensuring that the interview covers the key topics of interest.</p><p>Semi-structured interviews are typically conducted in person or over the phone, and are usually recorded for transcription and analysis. They can be used to gather data about a wide range of topics related to technology, such as people's experiences with specific products or systems, their attitudes towards technology in general, or their behaviors and practices related to technology use.</p><p>Semi-structured interviews are a valuable method in HCI research, as they provide rich and detailed data about people's experiences, attitudes, and behaviors related to technology. They can be particularly useful for understanding the subjective experiences of participants and for gaining insights into how people use technology in their everyday lives. They are also useful in obtaining more in-depth and nuanced data compared to survey-based methods.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semi-structured_interview" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p> 
		</method>

		<method id="thinkaloudexperts" category="formative,empirical,problems,experts" title="Qualitative Feedback: Expert Think-Aloud">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Think-Aloud method can also be used with experts, such as experts in a particular field or domain, or experts in the design and development of technology. This is known as Expert Think-Aloud.</p><p>When using the Think-Aloud method with experts, the researcher may ask the expert to perform a task or use a product or system while verbalizing their thoughts, just like with non-experts. However, in this case, experts are able to provide more in-depth and detailed verbalizations because they have more knowledge and experience in the specific field or domain.</p><p>Expert Think-Aloud can be particularly useful in evaluating the design and functionality of a product or system, as experts may have a more nuanced understanding of user needs and requirements. It can also be used to identify areas for improvement and to gather expert opinions on the design, usability, and functionality of a product or system.</p><p>However, it is important to keep in mind that experts may have different perspectives than end users, and their verbalizations may not always align with those of end users. Therefore, it is important to collect data from both experts and non-experts to gain a comprehensive understanding of the user's experience.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Think_aloud_protocol" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>  
		</method>

		<method id="thinkaloud" category="empirical,qualitative,subjective,randomsample" title="Qualitative Feedback: Think-Aloud">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Verbal statements from the participants to understand how people interact with digital products or systems, and to identify usability problems. It is a method of verbal protocol analysis in which participants are asked to think aloud, or verbalize their thoughts, as they perform a task or use a product or system. The method involves having participants speak out loud about what they are doing and thinking as they interact with the technology. This verbalization provides insight into the user's cognitive process as they interact with the technology and allows researchers to identify any problems or difficulties the user may encounter. This method is widely used in usability testing and user-centered design, as it allows researchers to identify usability issues and make design recommendations to improve the user experience.</p><p>The Think-Aloud method typically involves the following steps:</p><ul><li>  Participants are asked to complete a set of tasks while interacting with a product or system.</li><li> The verbalizations are recorded, either through audio or video recording, and later transcribed for analysis. </li><li>Researchers analyze the verbalizations to understand how participants interact with the technology, and identify any problems or difficulties they encounter.</li></ul> <p>The Think-Aloud method allows researchers to understand the user's thought process while they interact with the technology and provide insight into how they are interpreting and making sense of the interface. This method can be used as a supplement to other methods such as usability testing, surveys, and interviews, to gain a comprehensive understanding of the user's experience.</p> 
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Think_aloud_protocol" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>  
		</method>

		<method id="cit" category="empirical,problems,experts" title="Qualitative Feedback: Critical Incident Technique (CIT)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Critical Incident Technique (CIT) is a research method used to gather qualitative data about specific events or incidents that are considered critical or important in some way. CIT is widely used in various fields, including Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) to understand how people interact with technology, and to identify and analyze critical incidents related to technology use.</p><p>The CIT method involves asking participants to report on incidents that they have experienced related to the topic being studied. These incidents can be positive or negative, and can range from minor frustrations to major failures. Participants are asked to provide detailed descriptions of the incidents, including what happened, when, where, and how they felt about it.</p><p>Once the incidents are collected, they are analyzed and coded to identify common themes and patterns. The data can then be used to identify and understand critical incidents related to technology use, and to make design recommendations or to improve the usability and effectiveness of a product or system.</p><p>CIT is a valuable method in HCI research, as it allows researchers to gather rich and detailed data about critical incidents related to technology use. It can provide insights into how people interact with technology, and can be used to identify usability problems and design solutions. CIT is particularly useful when combined with other methods, such as surveys, interviews and usability testing, to gain a comprehensive understanding of the user's experience.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Critical_incident_technique" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>  
		</method>

		<method id="affinitydiagramming" category="formative,solutions,designprocess" title="Design Method: Affinity Diagram">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Affinity diagramming is a method used to organize and categorize information gathered during research or brainstorming sessions. It is a technique that helps to group ideas, thoughts, or data into related categories and identify patterns and connections.  The process of affinity diagramming begins by collecting a large amount of information, such as notes from interviews, observations, or brainstorming sessions.</p><p>This information is then written on sticky notes or cards and placed on a wall or board. Participants then work together to group the notes into related categories by moving the notes around and discussing the connections between them.  Once the notes are grouped into categories, the categories are given labels or names that summarize the main theme or idea of the group. These labels are then organized into a hierarchy, with higher-level categories representing broader themes and lower-level categories representing more specific ideas.</p><p>The output of affinity diagramming is a visual representation of the information that is easy to understand and navigate. It helps to identify patterns and connections in the data, and can be used to inform the design of products or services, generate ideas for research, or guide decision-making.  Affinity diagramming is a useful tool for bringing structure to large amounts of unstructured data, and it allows the group to work collaboratively and identify patterns and connections that might not be apparent otherwise. It's a powerful method to use in a team setting as it allows the team to have a shared understanding of the research or project.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Affinity_diagram" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p> 
		</method>

		<method id="participatorydesign" category="formative,solutions,designprocess" title="Design Method: Participatory Design">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Participatory design (PD) is a method used in human-computer interaction (HCI) and user-centered design to involve users in the design process. It is a technique that involves engaging users as active participants in the design process, rather than passive recipients of a design. This allows users to contribute their knowledge, skills, and perspectives to the design, leading to more usable and user-centered products.</p><p>Participatory design can take many forms, such as co-design sessions, workshops, focus groups, or ethnographic research. The goal of PD is to facilitate a collaborative design process between users and designers, where users and designers work together to understand the user's needs, goals, and constraints and to create designs that are tailored to their needs.</p><p>The process of participatory design typically involves creating a collaborative design environment where users and designers can work together to understand the user's needs, goals, and constraints, and to create designs that are tailored to their needs. This can involve using a variety of methods, such as brainstorming, affinity diagramming, card sorting, and prototyping.</p><p>Participatory design is a valuable tool for HCI designers because it allows them to involve users in the design process, which leads to more usable and user-centered products. It also allows designers to gain a deeper understanding of the user's needs, goals, and constraints, which can inform the design of the product or service. </p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Participatory_design" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p> 
			
		</method>

		<method id="physicalergonomics" category="formative,solutions,designprocess" title="Design Method: Physical Ergonomics">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Physical ergonomics is a sub-discipline of ergonomics that focuses on the physical aspects of human interactions with products, equipment, and environments. It aims to design and optimize products and environments to fit the physical capabilities and limitations of the people who use them.</p><p>Physical ergonomics is concerned with the design of products and environments to minimize physical strain, discomfort, and injury, and to promote ease of use, safety and productivity. It is applied to a wide range of products and environments, including furniture, equipment, tools, vehicles, buildings, and outdoor spaces.  Examples of physical ergonomics in practice include designing office chairs that adjust to the user's body shape, designing car interiors that accommodate different body sizes and shapes, and designing tools and equipment that are comfortable and easy to hold and use.</p><p>Physical ergonomics involves the application of anthropometry, which is the study of human body measurements, and biomechanics, which is the study of the mechanics of the human body. It also involves the use of tools such as anthropometric measurement data, biomechanical models, and simulation software to design and evaluate products and environments.</p><p>Physical ergonomics is essential for the design of products and environments that are safe, comfortable, and easy to use, especially for people with disabilities, older adults, and other populations with unique physical characteristics and needs.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human_factors_and_ergonomics#Physical_ergonomics" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>  
		</method>

		<method id="paralleldesign" category="formative,solutions,designprocess" title="Design Method: Parallel Design">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Parallel design is a method used in human-computer interaction (HCI) and user-centered design to simultaneously explore multiple design options and evaluate them with users. It is a technique that involves creating multiple design concepts in parallel and testing them with users to identify the best design solution.</p><p>The process of parallel design typically involves creating multiple design concepts, each of which addresses a specific design problem or goal. These concepts are then evaluated with users, who provide feedback on their preferences, strengths, and weaknesses. This allows the design team to identify the best design solution and make adjustments as needed.</p><p>Parallel design can be done using a variety of techniques, such as paper prototyping, wireframing, or digital prototyping. The choice of technique will depend on the goals of the evaluation, the resources available, and the level of detail required.  During the testing, users interact with the design concepts and the designer or facilitator can observe and note any issues or problems that arise. The design concepts can be used to test usability, user flow, and overall user experience.  Parallel design is a valuable tool for HCI designers because it allows them to explore multiple design options simultaneously, and evaluate them with users to identify the best design solution. It also allows designers to make changes and iterate on the design quickly, based on feedback from users.</p><p>Parallel design is considered a user-centered design method, as it puts the user at the center of the design process, by involving them in the evaluation of multiple design options. It's useful when testing a wide range of design options, when the goal is to test usability, user flow, and overall user experience, and when the budget and time allows it.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://www.usabilitybok.org/parallel-design" target="_blank">usabilitybok.org</a></p>  
		</method>

		<method id="functionallocation" category="formative,solutions,designprocess" title="Design Method: Function Allocation">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Function allocation is a method used in human-computer interaction (HCI) and systems engineering to determine the distribution of functions between human operators and computer systems. It is a technique that involves identifying the tasks and functions that are best suited to be performed by humans and the tasks and functions that are best suited to be performed by computer systems.</p><p>The process of function allocation typically involves identifying the functions and tasks that are required to complete a given task or process. These functions are then evaluated to determine which are best suited to be performed by humans and which are best suited to be performed by computer systems. Factors such as safety, efficiency, accuracy, and user preferences are considered when making these determinations.</p><p>Function allocation is important because it helps to ensure that the functions and tasks are performed by the most appropriate system, whether it is human or computer. This leads to more efficient, safe, and effective systems, as well as better user experiences.</p><p>Function allocation can be done using a variety of techniques, such as task analysis, functional analysis, and decision-making methods. The choice of technique will depend on the goals of the evaluation, the resources available, and the level of detail required.</p><p>Function allocation is essential for the design of systems that are safe, efficient, accurate, and easy to use. It's particularly useful in safety-critical systems such as aviation, nuclear power, and medical devices where the wrong allocation of functions could lead to severe consequences.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://www.usabilitybok.org/function-allocation" target="_blank">usabilitybok.org</a></p>  
		</method>

		<method id="cardsorting" category="formative,solutions,designprocess" title="Design Method: Card Sorting">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Card sorting is a method used in human-computer interaction (HCI) and user-centered design to understand how users organize and categorize information. It is a technique that helps to identify the most natural and meaningful grouping of information for a particular user group.</p><p>The process of card sorting typically involves creating a set of cards, each representing a piece of information or content. These cards are then given to a group of users, who are asked to organize them into categories or groups that make sense to them. This can be done in a physical or digital form.</p><p>There are two main types of card sorting: open and closed. In open card sorting, users are free to create their own categories and labels, whereas in closed card sorting, users are asked to sort the cards into predefined categories or groups.</p><p>The output of card sorting is a visual representation of the categories and groups that the users have created, along with the labels or names that they have assigned to them. This information can be used to inform the design of a website, application, or other digital product, by providing insights into how users expect to find and access information.</p><p>Card sorting is a valuable tool for HCI designers because it allows them to understand how users naturally think about and organize information. It can help to identify patterns and connections in the data, and can inform decisions about the organization, labeling, and navigation of a digital product.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Card_sorting" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>   
		</method>

		<method id="designthinking" category="formative,solutions,designprocess" title="Design Method: Design Thinking">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Design thinking is a problem-solving approach that is used in human-computer interaction (HCI) and user-centered design to understand and address the needs of users. It is a holistic and iterative process that involves empathizing with users, defining problems, ideating solutions, prototyping and testing. It is a human-centered approach that focuses on the needs and perspectives of users, rather than technical constraints or business goals.</p><p>The process of design thinking typically starts with understanding the needs and perspectives of users through techniques such as ethnographic research, interviews, and observations. Next, the problem is defined by synthesizing the research findings and identifying key issues and pain points. Then, a wide range of possible solutions are generated through brainstorming, mind-mapping, and other ideation techniques. After that, solutions are prototyped and tested with users to gather feedback and iterate on the design.</p><p>Design thinking is valuable in HCI and user-centered design because it helps to create products and services that are tailored to the needs and perspectives of users. It also allows for a more flexible and iterative design process, which leads to more innovative and effective solutions.</p><p>Design thinking is considered a user-centered design method, as it puts the user at the center of the design process. It is useful when the goal is to create products and services that are tailored to the needs and perspectives of users, when the goal is to generate new and innovative solutions, and when the goal is to create a flexible and iterative design process.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Design_thinking" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>    
		</method>

		<method id="contextualinquiry" category="formative,solutions,designprocess" title="Design Method: Contextual Inquiry">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Contextual inquiry is a method used in human-computer interaction (HCI) to understand how users interact with technology in their natural environment. The goal of contextual inquiry is to understand the user's goals, tasks, workflows, and processes, as well as their physical and social context. The method of contextual inquiry typically involves conducting interviews with users in their work or home environment, observing them as they perform tasks using technology, and collecting artifacts such as notes, sketches, and photographs. The data collected during contextual inquiry is used to identify patterns and problems in the user's workflow and to understand how the technology fits into the user's broader context. Contextual inquiry is a valuable tool for HCI designers because it provides a more complete understanding of how users interact with technology and how it fits into their daily lives. This information can be used to inform the design of technology that is better suited to the user's needs and is more likely to be used effectively. Contextual inquiry is considered a qualitative research method, meaning the data collected is non-numerical, and it's analyzed by identifying patterns, themes, and categories in the data. It's useful when the research question is open-ended, and the aim is to understand the user's experience.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contextual_inquiry" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>    
			
		</method>

		<method id="focusgroup" category="formative,solutions,designprocess" title="Design Method: Focus Group">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>A focus group is a method used in human-computer interaction (HCI) and user-centered design to gather qualitative data about user opinions, attitudes, and behaviors. It is a technique that involves bringing a small, diverse group of people together in a moderated discussion to explore a specific topic or product.</p><p>The process of conducting a focus group typically involves recruiting a group of participants who match specific demographic or user criteria, such as age, gender, occupation, or experience with a specific product. The group then meets in a moderated discussion, led by a facilitator, to explore a specific topic or product. The discussion is usually recorded, either through audio or video, and the data collected is analyzed to identify patterns, themes, and key issues related to the topic or product.</p><p>Focus groups are useful in HCI and user-centered design because they allow researchers to gather rich, detailed data about user opinions, attitudes, and behaviors. They also allow researchers to explore a specific topic or product in-depth and to gain a deeper understanding of the user's perspective.</p><p>Focus groups are considered a qualitative research method, as they involve collecting and analyzing data in a non-numerical format. They're particularly useful when the goal is to understand users' attitudes, opinions and behaviors about a specific topic or product, when the goal is to generate new insights and ideas, and when the goal is to gather feedback on a specific product or design.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Focus_group" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>   
			
		</method>

		<method id="storyboarding" category="formative,solutions,prototype" title="Design Method: Storyboarding">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Storyboarding is a method used in user-centered design and human-computer interaction (HCI) to visualize and communicate the design of an interface, product, or service. It is a technique that helps to plan and organize the user experience by creating a visual representation of the interactions and tasks that users will perform.</p><p>The process of storyboarding typically involves creating a series of drawings or illustrations that depict the different steps or screens in the user's journey. Each illustration is accompanied by notes or captions that describe the user's actions, thoughts, and feedback. The storyboard can be created using pencil and paper, digital tools, or a combination of both.</p><p>The output of storyboarding is a visual representation of the user experience that can be used to communicate the design to a wide range of stakeholders, including designers, developers, and users. It helps to identify potential issues or problems in the design and to make changes before the product or service is built.</p><p>Storyboarding is a valuable tool for HCI designers because it allows them to see the user's journey from start to finish and to identify potential issues or problems before they occur. It also helps to communicate the design to a wide range of stakeholders, including designers, developers, and users.</p><p>Storyboarding can also be used to create scenarios that capture the users' goals, needs, and expectations, and to evaluate the design against them. It's a powerful method to use when creating interactive products such as games, animations, and interactive web interfaces.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Storyboard#Software" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>    
		</method>

		<method id="mockup" category="formative,solutions,prototype" title="Prototyping Method: Image/Video MockUp">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Image/Video mockup is a method used in human-computer interaction (HCI) and user-centered design to create a visual representation of a design that can be used to test and evaluate it with users. It is a technique that involves creating a realistic image or video of the design, which can be used to simulate the look and feel of the final product.</p><p>The process of creating an image/video mockup typically involves using digital tools such as graphic design software, or specialized prototyping tools. The mockup is created to look as realistic as possible, and includes visual design elements such as color, typography, images, and even animations.</p><p>During the testing, users interact with the mockup, and the designer or facilitator can observe and note any issues or problems that arise. The mockup can be used to test the overall visual design, branding, and user experience.</p><p>Image/video mockup is a valuable tool for HCI designers because it allows them to test and evaluate the visual design of a product or service early in the design process, without the need for expensive or time-consuming software development. It also allows designers to make changes and iterate on the design quickly, based on feedback from users.</p><p>Image/video mockup is considered a high-fidelity prototyping method, as it's a realistic representation of the design, and it includes visual design elements. It's useful when testing mid or late-stage designs, when the goal is to test the overall visual design, branding, and user experience, and when the budget allows for it.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mockup" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>   
		</method>

		<method id="paperprototype" category="formative,solutions,prototype" title="Prototyping Method: Paper Prototype">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Paper prototyping is a method used in human-computer interaction (HCI) and user-centered design to test and evaluate designs with users. It is a technique that involves creating a rough, hand-drawn or printed representation of the design, which can be used to simulate interactions and test basic usability.</p><p>The process of paper prototyping typically involves creating a series of sketches or illustrations that depict the different screens or interactions of the design. These sketches can be created using pencil and paper, or printed from a digital tool. The sketches are then cut out and arranged on a board or table to simulate the different screens or interactions.</p><p>During the testing, a facilitator or designer acts as the system, and moves the paper sketches in response to the user's actions and input. This allows the user to interact with the design, and the designer to observe and note any issues or problems that arise.</p><p>Paper prototyping is a valuable tool for HCI designers because it is quick and easy to create, and it allows them to test basic usability and interactions early in the design process. It also allows designers to make changes and iterate on the design quickly, without the need for expensive or time-consuming software development.</p><p>Paper prototyping is considered a low-fidelity prototyping method, as it's a rough representation of the design, and the user's interactions are simulated rather than real. It's useful when testing early stage designs and when the goal is to test usability, user flow, and overall user experience.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paper_prototyping" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="rapidprototype" category="formative,solutions,prototype" title="Prototyping Method: Rapid Prototype">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Rapid prototyping is a method used in human-computer interaction (HCI) and user-centered design to quickly create a working model of a design, which can be tested and evaluated with users. The goal of rapid prototyping is to create a functional prototype of the design as quickly as possible, in order to test and evaluate it with users.</p><p>The process of rapid prototyping typically involves creating a prototype using simple and readily available materials, such as paper, cardboard, or foam board. The prototype is usually created quickly, and the focus is on functionality rather than aesthetics.</p><p>Rapid prototyping can be done using a variety of techniques, such as paper prototyping, wireframing, or 3D printing. The choice of technique will depend on the goals of the evaluation, the resources available, and the level of detail required.</p><p>During the testing, users interact with the prototype, and the designer or facilitator can observe and note any issues or problems that arise. The prototype can be used to test the functionality, usability, and overall user experience.</p><p>Rapid prototyping is a valuable tool for HCI designers because it allows them to test and evaluate the design early in the design process, without the need for expensive or time-consuming software development. It also allows designers to make changes and iterate on the design quickly, based on feedback from users.</p><p>Rapid prototyping is considered a low-fidelity prototyping method, as the prototype is usually created quickly, and the focus is on functionality rather than aesthetics. It's useful when testing early stage designs, when the goal is to test functionality, usability, and overall user experience, and when the budget or time is limited.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rapid_prototyping" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="wireframe" category="formative,solutions,prototype" title="Prototyping Method: Wireframe">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Wireframes are a method used in human-computer interaction (HCI) and user-centered design to test and evaluate designs with users. It is a technique that involves creating a simple, skeletal representation of the design, which can be used to test layout, navigation, and functionality.</p><p>A wireframe is a visual representation of the layout and structure of a website, application, or other digital product, without the use of visual design elements such as color, typography, or images. They are used to represent the interface and its layout, the organization of elements, and the relationships between them.</p><p>The process of creating wireframes typically involves using a digital tool such as a wireframing software, or just using pen and paper. The wireframe is created using simple shapes and lines, and includes the placement of elements such as buttons, text, images, and navigation elements.</p><p>During the testing, users interact with the wireframe, and the designer or facilitator can observe and note any issues or problems that arise. The wireframe can be used to test layout, navigation, and functionality, and to identify potential issues with the design before it is built.</p><p>Wireframes are a valuable tool for HCI designers because they allow them to test and evaluate the layout, navigation, and functionality of a design early in the design process. They also allow designers to make changes and iterate on the design quickly, without the need for expensive or time-consuming software development.</p><p>Wireframes are considered a low-fidelity prototyping method, as they lack visual design elements and details, and the user's interactions are simulated rather than real. They're useful when testing early stage designs, when the goal is to test layout, navigation, and functionality, and when the budget or time is limited.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Website_wireframe" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="storyboard" category="formative,solutions,prototype" title="Prototyping Method: Storyboard">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>A storyboard prototype is a method used in human-computer interaction (HCI) and user-centered design to create a visual representation of a product or service's user experience. It is a technique that involves creating a visual representation of the user's journey through the product or service in the form of a storyboard. A storyboard is a sequence of illustrations or images that depict the key steps or actions that a user takes when interacting with the product or service.</p><p>The process of creating a storyboard prototype typically involves identifying the key steps or actions that a user takes when interacting with the product or service, and creating illustrations or images that depict those steps or actions. The storyboard is then used to test and evaluate the user experience with users, and to identify any issues or problems that arise.</p><p>Storyboard prototypes are useful in HCI and user-centered design because they allow designers to create a visual representation of the user experience and test it with users early in the design process. They also allow designers to make changes and iterate on the design quickly, based on feedback from users.</p><p>Storyboard prototypes are considered a low-fidelity prototyping method, as they are a simplified representation of the design and do not include all the visual design elements. They are useful when testing early stage designs, when the goal is to test the overall user flow and user experience, and when the budget and time are limited.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Storyboard#Software" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="summativeusabilitytesting" category="summative,empirical,problems" title="Usability Inspection by Users: Summative Usability Testing">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Summative usability testing is a method used in human-computer interaction (HCI) and user-centered design to evaluate the usability and user experience of a product or service. It is a technique that involves testing the product or service with a representative sample of users to gather data on its usability and user experience.</p><p>The process of summative usability testing typically involves recruiting a representative sample of users who match specific demographic or user criteria, such as age, gender, occupation, or experience with a specific product. The users then perform a set of tasks or scenarios while their behavior is observed and recorded. The data collected is analyzed to identify patterns, themes, and key issues related to the usability and user experience of the product or service.</p><p>Summative usability testing is valuable in HCI and user-centered design because it allows researchers to gather data on the usability and user experience of a product or service, and to identify any issues or problems that arise. It also allows researchers to make data-driven decisions about the design of the product or service.</p><p>Summative usability testing is considered a quantitative research method, as it involves collecting and analyzing numerical data. It's particularly useful when the goal is to evaluate the usability and user experience of a final product or service, when the goal is to identify specific issues or problems with a product or service, and when the goal is to gather data to support design decisions.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://www.usabilitybok.org/summative-usability-testing" target="_blank">usabilitybok.org</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="benchmarktesting" category="formative,empirical,problems,experts" title="Usability Inspection by Users: Benchmark Testing">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Benchmark Testing is a method used to evaluate the usability of digital products or systems by having users perform tasks and then comparing their performance to a benchmark or standard.</p><p>In benchmark testing, a group of participants are asked to complete a set of tasks while interacting with a product or system. The performance of these participants is then compared to a benchmark, which can be an established standard or the performance of a similar group of participants on a similar product or system.</p><p>The benchmark can be established by performing a pilot study, where a group of participants complete the tasks and their performance is used as the benchmark. The results of the pilot study are used to establish a standard for future testing.</p><p>The main goal of benchmark testing is to identify areas for improvement and to compare the usability of different products or systems. The method is useful in identifying usability issues that might be overlooked in other methods such as surveys and interviews.</p><p>It is important to consider that benchmark testing is a comparative method, and it is not a standalone method for evaluating the usability of a product or system. Benchmark testing should be used in conjunction with other methods such as usability testing, expert reviews, and user interviews, to gain a comprehensive understanding of the user's experience.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://about.gitlab.com/handbook/engineering/ux/ux-research-training/usability-benchmarking" target="_blank">gitlab.com</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="remoteevaluation" category="formative,empirical,problems,experts" title="Usability Inspection by Users: Remote Evaluation">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Remote Evaluation is a method used in Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) to evaluate the usability of digital products or systems remotely. This method allows researchers to conduct evaluations remotely rather than in a lab setting. Remote evaluations are conducted over the internet and can be carried out from anywhere and at any time, making it possible to test products or systems with users in different locations and time zones.</p><p>Remote evaluations can be conducted in different ways, such as having participants complete a set of tasks while interacting with a product or system and then providing feedback on their experience. The feedback can be in the form of written comments, video recordings, or audio recordings.</p><p>Remote evaluations have several advantages over traditional in-person evaluations. They allow researchers to test products or systems with a larger and more diverse group of users, and they make it possible to test products or systems in a more natural setting. Remote evaluations are also more cost-effective and time-efficient, as they do not require participants to travel to a lab or testing facility.</p><p>However, it is important to note that remote evaluations have some limitations, such as the lack of control over the testing environment and potential technical difficulties. Additionally, remote evaluations may not provide the same level of detail as in-person evaluations, as researchers do not have direct access to the user's environment or body language. Therefore, it is important to use multiple methods to gain a comprehensive understanding of the user's experience.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://www.usabilitybok.org/remote-evaluation" target="_blank">usabilitybok.org</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="heuristicevaluation" category="formative,empirical,problems,experts" title="Usability Inspection by Experts: Heuristic Evaluation">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Heuristic Evaluation is a method used in Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) to evaluate the usability of digital products or systems. It is a formal method for identifying usability problems by having a group of experts evaluate the product or system against a set of established usability principles, known as heuristics.</p><p>In Heuristic Evaluation, a group of experts, such as usability specialists, interaction designers, or user experience designers, are asked to evaluate a product or system against a set of established heuristics. These heuristics are a set of general principles for good design, such as consistency, visibility of system status, and error prevention.</p><p>The experts are asked to identify any usability issues that they find while using the product or system, and to provide detailed descriptions of the issues and how they relate to the heuristics. The experts then meet to discuss the issues and to prioritize them based on their severity and impact on the user.</p><p>Heuristic Evaluation is a valuable method in HCI research, as it allows researchers to identify usability problems early in the design process, before they become more costly and time-consuming to fix. It is also cost-effective, as it only requires a small number of experts to evaluate the product or system. However, it's important to note that Heuristic Evaluation is a comparative method, and it is not a standalone method for evaluating the usability of a product or system. Heuristic Evaluation should be used in conjunction with other methods such as usability testing, expert reviews, and user interviews, to gain a comprehensive understanding of the user's experience.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heuristic_evaluation" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="consistencyinspection" category="empirical,problems,experts" title="Usability Inspection by Experts: Consistency Inspection">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Consistency Inspection is a method used to evaluate the consistency of a digital product or system. Consistency refers to the degree to which the product or system's user interface elements, such as layout, wording, icons, and interactions, are consistent throughout the product. Consistency is important because it helps users to understand and predict the behavior of the system, and reduces the cognitive load on the user.</p><p>Consistency Inspection is usually done by having a group of experts, such as usability specialists, interaction designers, or user experience designers, evaluate the product or system for consistency. The experts are asked to identify any inconsistencies they find and to provide detailed descriptions of the issues.</p><p>During the inspection, experts are looking for things like consistent use of layout, wording, icons, and interactions across all the pages, or screens of the product, as well as consistency in the use of error messages, feedback, and help functions.</p><p>Consistency Inspection is a valuable method in HCI research, as it allows researchers to identify inconsistencies early in the design process, before they become more costly and time-consuming to fix. It is also cost-effective, as it only requires a small number of experts to evaluate the product or system. However, it's important to note that Consistency Inspection is a comparative method, and it is not a standalone method for evaluating the consistency of a product or system. Consistency Inspection should be used in conjunction with other methods such as usability testing, expert reviews, and user interviews, to gain a comprehensive understanding of the user's experience.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Usability#Inspection_methods" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="pluralisticinspection" category="formative,empirical,problems,experts" title="Usability Inspection by Experts: Pluralistic inspection">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Pluralistic Inspection is a method used to evaluate the usability of a digital product or system by combining the results from multiple inspection methods. It can involve a combination of different inspection methods, such as Heuristic Evaluation, Cognitive Walkthrough, and Consistency Inspection, to identify usability problems.</p><p>The idea behind Pluralistic Inspection is that different inspection methods have different strengths and weaknesses, and by using multiple methods, researchers can gain a more comprehensive understanding of the usability issues. For example, Heuristic Evaluation can identify usability problems early in the design process, while usability testing can identify issues that arise during real-world use.</p><p>During Pluralistic Inspection, each inspection method is applied to the product or system, and the results are then combined and compared to identify common issues and prioritize them based on their severity and impact on the user.</p><p>Pluralistic Inspection is a valuable method in HCI research, as it allows researchers to identify usability problems early in the design process, before they become more costly and time-consuming to fix. It also provides a more comprehensive understanding of the user's experience by combining the results from multiple methods. However, it is important to keep in mind that Pluralistic Inspection can be time-consuming and resource-intensive, as it requires the use of multiple methods.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Usability#Inspection_methods" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="activityanalysis" category="formative,empirical,problems,experts" title="Usability Inspection by Experts: Activity Analysis">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Activity Analysis is a method used to understand how experts interact with digital products or systems, and to identify opportunities for improvement. It is a method used to study the activities, tasks, and processes that experts perform while using a product or system.</p><p>Activity Analysis involves observing experts as they perform tasks and use a product or system, and then analyzing their actions, behaviors, and interactions. This can be done through methods such as observation, interviews, and diary studies.</p><p>During the analysis, researchers look for patterns and trends in the data, and use this information to identify opportunities for improvement. For example, they might identify areas where users are struggling, or where the system could be made more efficient.</p><p>Activity Analysis is a valuable method in HCI research, as it provides insight into how people actually use a product or system, rather than just what they say they do. It can be used to identify usability problems and to make design recommendations to improve the user experience. It is also useful in identifying unanticipated use cases and new opportunities for a product or system. It can be used in combination with other methods such as usability testing, expert reviews, and user interviews, to gain a comprehensive understanding of the user's experience.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Usability#Inspection_methods" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="taskanalysis" category="formative,analytical,datadriven" title="Data-driven Analysis: Cognitive/Hierarchical Task Analysis (CTA/HTA)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Cognitive Task Analysis (CTA) and Hierarchical Task Analysis (HTA) are data-driven methods for understanding how people perform tasks and interact with digital products or systems. They are used to identify the mental processes and strategies that people use to complete tasks, as well as the structure and organization of tasks.</p><p>CTA is a method that allows researchers to understand the mental processes and strategies that people use to complete tasks. It typically involves collecting data through methods such as observation, interviews, and think-aloud protocols. The data is analyzed to identify the specific mental processes and strategies used by the users, such as problem-solving, decision-making, and memory.</p><p>HTA, on the other hand, is a method that helps researchers to understand the structure and organization of tasks. It involves breaking down tasks into smaller and more manageable subtasks and then organizing these subtasks into a hierarchical structure. This hierarchical structure shows the relationship between subtasks and the order in which they need to be completed. This data is collected through methods such as observation, interviews, and task decomposition.</p><p>Both CTA and HTA are valuable methods in HCI research, as they provide a comprehensive understanding of how people interact with digital products or systems. By identifying mental processes, strategies, and task structure, researchers can identify areas for improvement and make design recommendations to enhance the user experience.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://www.usabilitybok.org/hierarchical-task-analysis" target="_blank">usabilitybok.org</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="groundedtheory" category="formative,analytical,datadriven" title="Data-driven Analysis: Grounded Theory">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Grounded Theory is a research method used in Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) to generate a theoretical understanding of a phenomenon through the analysis of data. It is an inductive method that allows researchers to generate theory from data, rather than testing a preconceived theory.</p><p>Grounded Theory is typically used in qualitative research and it involves collecting and analyzing data, such as interviews, observations, or written documents, to identify patterns, themes, and relationships. The data is analyzed repeatedly to identify emerging patterns, and these patterns are used to generate a theoretical framework that explains the phenomenon being studied.</p><p>The coding process typically includes the following steps:</p><ol><li>Open coding: This is the initial stage of coding, where the data is read and broken down into small chunks of information, called "codes." Codes are assigned to specific segments of the data, based on the content and meaning.</li><li>Axial coding: This stage involves grouping the codes into broader categories, based on similarities and relationships.</li><li>Selective coding: This stage involves identifying the core category, which is the central concept that connects all the other categories.</li><li>Memo writing: Memos are written to document the researcher's thoughts and observations about the data and the emerging categories.</li><li>Constant comparison: This is an ongoing process where new data is compared to the existing codes and categories to identify similarities and differences, and to refine the coding scheme as needed.</li></ol><p>These coding steps are iterative and cyclical, meaning that the researcher will repeatedly go back and forth between the different coding steps to ensure that the codes, categories, and theoretical framework accurately reflect the data.</p><p>The goal of coding is to identify patterns and relationships in the data and to generate a theoretical framework that explains the phenomenon being studied. Coding is an essential step in Grounded Theory, as it allows researchers to make sense of the data and to generate a comprehensive theoretical framework.</p><p>Grounded Theory is a valuable method in HCI research as it allows researchers to generate theory from data, rather than testing a preconceived theory. It also allows researchers to identify patterns and relationships that might not be obvious from the data alone. It's also useful in identifying new opportunities and unanticipated use cases. However, it's important to keep in mind that Grounded Theory is a time-consuming method and it requires a significant amount of data to generate a comprehensive theoretical framework.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grounded_theory" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="personas" category="formative,analytical,datadriven" title="Data-driven Analysis: Personas">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Personas, or fictional characters based on user research and feedback, have revolutionized Human-Computer Interaction and created a personalized experience for users. In today's world, technology plays a prevalent role in everyday life, and it is increasingly important to ensure that users have an efficient and enjoyable experience when interacting with such technology. This essay will discuss the concept of personas and their role in human-computer interaction, highlighting how their implementation has allowed users to have a tailored experience.</p><p>Personas are especially useful for uncovering the nuances of the people’s characteristics and requirements. Through user research and personas, designers can create products and services that are tailored to the needs, while also taking into consideration their physical, cognitive, and emotional capacities.</p><p>Data-Driven Personas (DDP) are an increasingly popular human-computer interaction (HCI) technique for understanding user behavior. According to Jansen, Salminen, Jung, and Guan (2021), DDPs “are generated from user data such as demographics, interests, behavior, and preferences” and are used to “make more informed product decisions”. As the authors note, DDPs are a powerful tool for understanding user behavior and providing tailored experiences that meet user needs. Furthermore, they can be used alongside other HCI techniques such as user research and interviews to further understand user behavior. By combining information gathered through user research and interviews with insights gained through DDPs, designers and developers can create user experiences that are tailored to the specific needs of their users. Additionally, DDPs can be used to identify and address areas of user dissatisfaction that may not be picked up by other HCI techniques. In conclusion, DDPs are an effective tool for understanding user behavior and should be used alongside other HCI techniques to create user experiences that are tailored to the specific needs of the users.</p> 
			<p><strong>Source:</strong>BJ Jansen. , J Salminen. , S Jung. , K Guan. Using Data-Driven Personas Alongside Other Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) Techniques. Springer, DOI: <a href="https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-031-02231-9_8" target='_blank'>10.1007/978-3-031-02231-9_8</a></p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://www.usabilitybok.org/persona" target='_blank'>Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="fittsmodel" category="analytical,modeldriven" title="Model-driven Analysis: Fitts' Law">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Fitts's law (often cited as Fitts' law) is a predictive model of human movement primarily used in human–computer interaction and ergonomics. Over the years, different variations of the original law have been used in various HCI projects to further study the behavior of the user and design better user experiences. In this essay, I will discuss the various aspects of Fitts Law and explain how it has been utilized in the field of HCI such as for 2D or 3D.<p></p>The law predicts that the time required to rapidly move to a target area is a function of the ratio between the distance to the target and the width of the target. For a model-driven analysis a device's constants (a and b) in his formula [1] must be known.<p></p>Fitts's law is used to model the act of pointing, either by physically touching an object with a hand or finger, or virtually, by pointing to an object on a computer monitor using a pointing device. Furthermore, it has been used to investigate how users interact with touchscreens, such as those found in mobile phones and tablet computers. As such, Fitts law is an important research and design tool that can be used to improve the user experience of HCI.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fitts%27s_law" target='_blank'>Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="goms" category="analytical,modeldriven" title="Model-driven Analysis: Goals, Operators, Methods, and Selection (GOMS)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>GOMS, or Goals, Operators, Methods, and Selection, is an important and popular model for analyzing user interfaces in human-computer interaction. GOMS is effective when it comes to studying complex.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CPM-GOMS" target='_blank'>Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="cpmgoms" category="analytical,modeldriven" title="Model-driven Analysis: Cognitive Perceptual Motor GOMS (CPM-GOMS)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>GOMS is a specialized human information processor model for human-computer interaction observation that describes a user's cognitive structure on four components. In the book The Psychology of Human Computer Interaction. written in 1983 by Stuart K. Card, Thomas P. Moran and Allen Newell, the authors introduce: "a set of Goals, a set of Operators, a set of Methods for achieving the goals, and a set of Selections rules for choosing among competing methods for goals." GOMS is a widely used method by usability specialists for computer system designers because it produces quantitative and qualitative predictions of how people will use a proposed system.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GOMS" target='_blank'>Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="cmngoms" category="analytical,modeldriven" title="Model-driven Analysis: Card, Moran and Newell GOMS (CMN-GOMS)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>CMN-GOMS is the original GOMS model proposed by Stuart Card, Thomas P. Moran and Allen Newell. CMN stands for Card, Moran and Newell and it takes the KLM as its basic and adds subgoals and selection rules. This model can predict operator sequence as well as execution time. A CMN-GOMS model can be represented in program form, making it amenable to analysis as well as execution. CMN-GOMS has been used to model word processors and CAD systems for ergonomic design(see CAD). The CMN method can predict the operator sequence and the execution time of a task on a quantitative level and can focus its attention on methods to accomplish goals on a qualitative level.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GOMS#CMN-GOMS" target='_blank'>Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="ngomsl" category="analytical,modeldriven" title="Model-driven Analysis: Structured Natural Language GOMS (CMN-GOMS)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>NGOMSL is a structured natural language notation for representing GOMS models and a procedure for constructing them. This program form provides predictions of operator sequences, execution time and time to learn methods. An analyst constructs an NGOMSL model by performing a top-down, breadth-first expansion of the user's top-level goals into methods, until the methods contain only primitive operators, typically keystroke-level operators. This model explicitly represents the goal structure just like the CMN-GOMS and can so represent high-level goals.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong>  <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GOMS#NGOMSL" target='_blank'>Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="sgoms" category="analytical,modeldriven" title="Model-driven Analysis: Sociotechnical GOMS (CMN-GOMS)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>SGOMS stands for Sociotechnical GOMS and was created to allow GOMS to model work in complex sociotechnical systems. GOMS is meant to model an individual user, working in isolation, with no unexpected interruptions, similar to a Cognitive Psychology experiment. This level of analysis is sometimes referred to as microcognition to distinguish it from macrocognition, which refers to real world cognition. SGOMS is meant to expand the applicability of GOMS to the macro cognitive level of analysis. To do this, SGOMS adds a high level control structure to GOMS, called the planning unit. This allows GOMS to deal with unexpected interruptions.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GOMS#SGOMS" target='_blank'>Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="klm" category="analytical,modeldriven" title="Model-driven Analysis: Keystroke-level Model (KLM)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>In human–computer interaction, the keystroke-level model (KLM) predicts how long it will take an expert user to accomplish a routine task without errors using an interactive computer system. It was proposed by Stuart K. Card, Thomas P. Moran and Allen Newell in 1980 in the Communications of the ACM and published in their book The Psychology of Human-Computer Interaction in 1983, which is considered as a classic in the HCI field. The foundations were laid in 1974, when Card and Moran joined the Palo Alto Research Center (PARC) and created a group named Applied Information-Processing Psychology Project (AIP) with Newell as a consultant aiming to create an applied psychology of human-computer interaction. The keystroke-level model is still relevant today, which is shown by the recent research about mobile phones and touchscreens (see Adaptions).</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keystroke-level_model" target='_blank'>Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="cognitivewalkthrough" category="formative,empirical,problems,experts" title="Usability Inspection by Experts: Cognitive walkthrough">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The cognitive walkthrough method is a usability inspection method used to identify usability issues in interactive systems, focusing on how easy it is for new users to accomplish tasks with the system. A cognitive walkthrough is task-specific, whereas heuristic evaluation takes a holistic view to catch problems not caught by this and other usability inspection methods. The method is rooted in the notion that users typically prefer to learn a system by using it to accomplish tasks, rather than, for example, studying a manual. The method is prized for its ability to generate results quickly with low cost, especially when compared to usability testing, as well as the ability to apply the method early in the design phases before coding even begins (which happens less often with usability testing).</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognitive_walkthrough" target='_blank'>Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="eyetracking" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,attention" title="Quantitative Objective Attention: Eye Tracking Fixations">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Eye tracking is the process of measuring either the point of gaze (where one is looking) or the motion of an eye relative to the head. An eye tracker is a device for measuring eye positions and eye movement. Eye trackers are used in research on the visual system, in psychology, in psycholinguistics, marketing, as an input device for human-computer interaction, and in product design. Eye movements are typically divided into fixations and saccades - when the eye gaze pauses in a certain position, and when it moves to another position, respectively. The resulting series of fixations and saccades is called a <strong>scanpath</strong>. Smooth pursuit describes the eye following a moving object. Fixational eye movements include microsaccades: small, involuntary saccades that occur during attempted fixation. Most information from the eye is made available during a fixation or smooth pursuit, but not during a saccade.</p> 
			<p><strong>Reference Guide:</strong> Holmqvist, K., Nyström, M., Andersson, R., Dewhurst, R., Jarodzka, H., and Van de Weijer, J. (2011). Eye tracking: A comprehensive guide to methods and measures. OUP Oxford.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eye-Tracking" target='_blank'>Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="crs" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,ergonomics" title="Quantitative Subjective Ergonomics: Comfort Rating Scales (CRS)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Comfort Rating Scale (CRS) is a tool used in Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) research to measure the comfort level of users when interacting with technology. The CRS measure wearable comfort across 6 dimensions. These dimensions are Emotion, Attachment, Harm, Perceived change, Movement, and Anxiety.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong> F. Knight, C. Baber, A. Schwirtz and H. W. Bristow, "The comfort assessment of wearable computers," Proceedings. Sixth International Symposium on Wearable Computers,, Seattle, WA, USA, 2002, pp. 65-72, DOI: <a href="https://doi.org/10.1109/ISWC.2002.1167220">https://doi.org/10.1109/ISWC.2002.1167220</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="rula" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,ergonomics" title="Quantitative Objective Ergonomics: Rapid Upper Limb Assessment (RULA)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Rapid Upper Limb Assessment (RULA) score is a tool used in Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) research to evaluate and assess the ergonomic risks associated with the use of computer workstations. RULA is used to evaluate the postures of workers while they are working with computers and identify any potential ergonomic hazards that may arise. The tool assesses postures based on two main upper limb regions: the neck/shoulder region and the wrist/hand region. The RULA tool assigns a score between 1 and 7 for each region, with higher scores indicating a greater degree of ergonomic risk. The final RULA score is obtained by combining the two region scores to obtain an overall score ranging from 1 to 7. RULA is a useful tool for HCI practitioners and researchers as it allows them to identify and mitigate potential ergonomic hazards associated with computer use. By assessing postures and identifying areas for improvement, RULA can help to prevent musculoskeletal disorders and improve overall user comfort and well-being.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong> McAtamney L, Nigel Corlett E. RULA: a survey method for the investigation of work-related upper limb disorders. Appl Ergon. 1993 Apr. 24(2), 91-9. DOI: <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/0003-6870(93)90080-S">10.1016/0003-6870(93)90080-s</a></p>
			<p><strong>Download: </strong><a target="_blank" href="https://hci-studies.org/methods-and-measures/downloads/RULA-Guide-v-5.0.pdf">A Step-by-Step Guide to the RULA Assessment Tool</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="reba" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,ergonomics" title="Quantitative Objective Ergonomics: Rapid Entire Body Assessment (REBA)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Rapid Entire Body Assessment (REBA) score is a tool used in Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) research to evaluate and assess the ergonomic risks associated with the use of computer workstations. REBA is a systematic observational method that analyzes the entire body postures of workers and identifies potential ergonomic hazards that may arise during their work. The tool assesses postures based on a range of factors, including the angle of body segments and the frequency and duration of the work activity. The REBA tool assigns a score for each body segment, with higher scores indicating a greater degree of ergonomic risk. The final REBA score is obtained by combining the scores for each body segment to obtain an overall score. REBA is a useful tool for HCI practitioners and researchers as it allows them to identify and mitigate potential ergonomic hazards associated with computer use. By assessing postures and identifying areas for improvement, REBA can help to prevent musculoskeletal disorders and improve overall user comfort and well-being. However, it's important to note that REBA was designed to assess a broad range of manual work activities and may not be as well suited for assessing the ergonomic risks of computer workstations compared to more specific tools like RULA (Rapid Upper Limb Assessment).</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong> Hignett, Sue and Mcatamney, Lynn. (2000). Rapid entire body assessment (REBA). Applied ergonomics. 31. 201-5. DOI: <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/s0003-6870(99)00039-3">10.1016/S0003-6870(99)00039-3</a></p>
			<p><strong>Download: </strong><a target="_blank" href="https://hci-studies.org/methods-and-measures/downloads/REBA-Guide-v-5.0.pdf">A Step-by-Step Guide to the REBA Assessment Tool</a></p> 
		</method>

		<method id="niosh" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,ergonomics" title="Quantitative Objective Ergonomics: The NIOSH Lifting Equation">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The NIOSH Lifting Equation is widely accepted as valid in the field of occupational ergonomics, providing occupational health and safety professionals an objective ergonomic risk assessment tool for manual material handling tasks. The NIOSH Lifting Equation is a great way to identify ergonomic opportunities and prioritize ergonomic improvement efforts, and it also provides an objective baseline from which you can document ergonomic improvements.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Waters, T. R., Putz-Anderson, V., and Garg, A. (1994). Applications manual for the revised NIOSH lifting equation, <a href="https://stacks.cdc.gov/view/cdc/5434">https://stacks.cdc.gov/view/cdc/5434</a></p>
			<p><strong>Download: </strong><a target="_blank" href="https://hci-studies.org/methods-and-measures/downloads/NIOSH-guide-v-5.5.pdf">A Step-by-Step Guide to the NIOSH Lifting Equation</a></p> 
		</method> 

		<method id="rsq" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,stress" title="Quantitative Subjective Stress: Relaxation State Questionnaire (RSQ)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Relaxation State Questionnaire (RSQ) is a self-report measure designed to assess an individual's subjective experience of relaxation. The RSQ consists of 10 items, which are rated on a 5-point Likert scale from "strongly disagree" to "strongly agree." The questionnaire measures four dimensions of relaxation experience: muscle, sleepiness, cardiovascular, and general relaxation.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong> Steghaus, S., and Poth, C. H. (2022). Assessing momentary relaxation using the Relaxation State Questionnaire (RSQ). Scientific Reports, 12(1), 16341. DOI: <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-022-20524-w">10.1038/s41598-022-20524-w</a></p> 
		</method> 

		<method id="psq" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,stress" title="Quantitative Subjective Stress: Perceived Stress Questionnaire (PSQ)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Perceived Stress Questionnaire (PSQ) is a self-report measure designed to assess an individual's perception of stress in their life. The questionnaire was developed by Levenstein and colleagues in 1993 and has been widely used in research and clinical settings to evaluate the impact of stress on health and well-being. The PSQ consists of 30 items, which are rated on a 4-point Likert scale from "almost never" to "almost always." The questionnaire measures four dimensions of perceived stress: stressors, worries, tension, and lack of joy. Stressors refer to the degree to which the individual perceives their life events and circumstances as stressful. Worries refer to the degree to which the individual experiences anxiety and concerns about their future. Tension refers to the degree to which the individual experiences physical and psychological tension and discomfort. Lack of joy refers to the degree to which the individual experiences a lack of pleasure and enjoyment in their life.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong> Levenstein, S., Prantera, C., Varvo, V., Scribano, M. L., Berto, E., Luzi, C., and Andreoli, A. (1993). Development of the Perceived Stress Questionnaire: a new tool for psychosomatic research. Journal of psychosomatic research, 37(1), 19-32. DOI: <a href="https://doi.org/10.23668/psycharchives.2889">10.23668/psycharchives.2889</a></p> 
			<p><strong>Link: </strong> <a href="https://www.testarchiv.eu/de/test/9004426">Perceived Stress Questionnaire</a></p> 
		</method>

		<method id="wearscale" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,socialacceptance" title="Quantitative Subjective Social Acceptance: Wearable Acceptability Range (WEAR Scale v.3)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The WEAR scale (v.3) is a measure that has been developed to understand the factors that affect the social acceptability of wearable devices and to predict their acceptance. The development of the scale involved defining the construct "social acceptability of a wearable" and creating an initial item pool, which was reviewed by experts. The resulting scale was administered to sample respondents along with similar scales for validation purposes. Factor analysis resulted in a two-factor, fourteen-item solution (WEAR v.3) that was consistent among the three datasets. The WEAR v.3 scale demonstrates good reliability and construct validity, and provides valuable information for academia and industry, including predictive modeling, theory-building, and wearable development and applications. The factors affecting the social acceptability of wearable devices include manners, moral codes, the symbolic communication of dress, habits of dress, fashion, context of use, form, and aesthetics.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong> Kelly, Norene, The WEAR Scale: Development of a measure of the social acceptability of a wearable device (2016). Graduate Theses and Dissertations. 15230.</p>
			<p><strong>Download: </strong><a target="_blank" href="https://core.ac.uk/download/pdf/46556221.pdf">The WEAR Scale</a> (PhD Thesis by Norene Kelly, Final WEAR Scale v.3 can be found on p. 176)</p> 
		</method>

		<method id="uvq" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,humanlikeness" title="Quantitative Subjective Human-Likeness: Uncanny Valley Questionnaire (UVQ)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Uncanny Valley Questionnaire (UVQ) is a psychological instrument that is used to measure the human response to humanoid robots or other artificial agents that resemble humans but are not quite perfect. The "uncanny valley" refers to the idea that as a robot or artificial agent becomes more human-like in appearance and behavior, there is a point at which it becomes eerily similar to a human but not quite human enough, causing a sense of revulsion or discomfort in humans. The UVQ is designed to assess this effect by asking participants to rate the familiarity, human-likeness, and eeriness of different artificial agents, including robots, virtual characters, and prosthetic limbs. The UVQ has been used in various studies to investigate the relationship between human responses and different aspects of the appearance and behavior of humanoid robots, and it has proven to be a useful tool for understanding the psychological factors that influence the acceptance and adoption of these types of technologies.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Chin-Chang, H., and MacDorman, K. F. (2017). Measuring the Uncanny Valley Effect. International Journal of Social Robotics, 9(1), 129-139. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s12369-016-0380-9">10.1007/s12369-016-0380-9</a></p>
			<p><strong>Download: </strong><a target="_blank" href="http://www.macdorman.com/kfm/writings/pubs/Ho-MacDorman-2017-Measuring-Uncanny-Valley-Effect-Refinements-to-Indices-for-Perceived-Humanness-Attractiveness-Eeriness-IJSR.pdf">Measuring the Uncanny Valley Effect</a> (Table 2)</p> 
		</method>

		<method id="scm" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,socialacceptance" title="Quantitative Subjective Social Acceptance: Stereotype Content Model (SCM)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The stereotype content model (SCM) is a social psychological theory that proposes that people form stereotypes about social groups based on two primary dimensions: warmth and competence. Warmth refers to how friendly and well-intentioned a group is perceived to be, while competence refers to how capable and skilled a group is perceived to be. According to the SCM, people's perceptions of social groups along these dimensions influence their attitudes and behaviors towards those groups. Specifically, groups that are perceived as warm and competent are likely to be highly regarded and socially accepted, while groups that are perceived as cold and incompetent are likely to be marginalized and discriminated against. For example, the stereotype that women are warm but less competent than men can lead to their exclusion from leadership positions in certain domains. Similarly, the stereotype that certain racial or ethnic groups are less competent can lead to discrimination in hiring or educational opportunities. Overall, the SCM helps to explain how stereotypes and social acceptance are linked, and it underscores the importance of addressing stereotypes in promoting social equality and inclusion.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Fiske, S. T., Cuddy, A. J., Glick, P., and Xu, J. (2002). A model of (often mixed) stereotype content: competence and warmth respectively follow from perceived status and competition. Journal of personality and social psychology, 82(6), 878. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1037%2F0022-3514.82.6.878">10.1037%2F0022-3514.82.6.878</a></p>
			<p><strong>Download: </strong><a target="_blank" href="https://cos.gatech.edu/facultyres/Diversity_Studies/Fiske_StereotypeContent.pdf">A model of (often mixed) stereotype content: competence and warmth respectively follow from perceived status and competition</a> (Table 2, Table 7)</p>
		</method>

		<method id="tam" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,socialacceptance" title="Quantitative Subjective Social Acceptance: Technology Acceptance Model (TAM)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Technology Acceptance Model (TAM) is a widely used theoretical framework that helps researchers and practitioners understand and predict the acceptance and usage of new technologies by individuals. TAM was first introduced in the 1980s by Davis, Bagozzi, and Warshaw and has since been revised several times to incorporate new factors and variables. TAM 3.0 is the latest version of the model, which was developed by Venkatesh and colleagues in 2012. It includes new constructs such as Perceived Enjoyment and Perceived Social Norms and also integrates some of the previous extensions made to the original model. TAM 3.0 is an improvement over previous versions because it provides a more comprehensive and accurate understanding of users' attitudes and intentions towards technology adoption. By using TAM 3.0, researchers and practitioners can better identify the factors that affect user acceptance and tailor their interventions accordingly. This can lead to more successful technology implementations and better outcomes for both individuals and organizations.</p>
			<p><strong>Source (TAM): </strong>Davis, F., Bagozzi, P. and Warshaw, P. (1989), ‘User acceptance of computer technology - a comparison of two theoretical models’, Management Science 35(8), 982–1003.</p>
			<p><strong>Source (TAM3): </strong>Venkatesh, V., and Bala, H. (2008). Technology acceptance model 3 and a research agenda on interventions. Decision sciences, 39(2), 273-315.</p>
			<p><strong>Download (TAM3): </strong><a target="_blank" href="https://core.ac.uk/download/pdf/144826641.pdf">Technology Acceptance Model</a> (p. 313 - 314)</p>
		</method>

		<method id="utaut" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,socialacceptance" title="Quantitative Subjective Social Acceptance: User Acceptance of Information Technology Model (UTAUT)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Unified Theory of Acceptance and Use of Technology (UTAUT) is a model developed through a review of eight prominent models of user acceptance of information technology (IT). UTAUT was empirically validated using data from four organizations and found to outperform the eight individual models in explaining the variance in user intentions to use IT. UTAUT consists of four core determinants of intention and usage, and up to four moderators of key relationships, making it a useful tool for managers to assess the likelihood of success for new technology introductions and design interventions targeted at users who may be less inclined to adopt and use new systems. The paper also makes recommendations for future research.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Venkatesh V, Morris MG, Davis GB, Davis FD. User Acceptance of Information Technology: Toward a Unified View. MIS Quarterly. 2003;27(3):425-478. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.2307/30036540">10.2307/30036540</a></p>  
			<p><strong>Link: </strong><a target="_blank" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unified_theory_of_acceptance_and_use_of_technology">Wikipedia</a></p> 
		</method>

		<method id="imi" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,motivation" title="Quantitative Subjective Motivation: Intrinsic Motivation Inventory (IMI)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Intrinsic Motivation Inventory (IMI) is a self-report measure designed to assess an individual's intrinsic motivation, or the internal drive to engage in an activity for its own sake, rather than for external rewards or pressures. The IMI was developed by Richard Ryan and Edward Deci in 1985, and has been widely used in research studies across various domains, including education, sports, and health. Respondents rate each item on a Likert scale, with higher scores indicating greater levels of intrinsic motivation. The IMI has been shown to have good reliability and validity, and has been used in a wide range of research studies examining the effects of various interventions on intrinsic motivation. It is widely regarded as a valuable tool for researchers and practitioners who are interested in understanding and fostering intrinsic motivation.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Deci, E. L., and Ryan, R. M. (2013). Intrinsic motivation and self-determination in human behavior. Springer Science and Business Media.</p>
			<p><strong>Download: </strong><a target="_blank" href="https://hci-studies.org/methods-and-measures/downloads/IMI_Complete.pdf">Using the Intrinsic Motivation Inventory (IMI)</a></p>
		</method> 

		<method id="umi" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,motivation" title="Quantitative Subjective Motivation: User Motivation Inventory (UMI)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The User Motivation Inventory (UMI) is designed to assess the motivation of users to engage with interactive systems. The UMI is an 18-item multidimensional measure rooted in self-determination theory (SDT), and it measures intrinsic motivation, integrated, identified, introjected, and external regulation, as well as amotivation. The UMI has been found to have high reliability and convergent and discriminant validity for each subscale in two studies involving a total of 941 participants. The UMI has been shown to detect differences in motivation for people who consider abandoning a technology compared to those who do not question their use. The abstract concludes by discussing the central role of motivation in users' behavior and experience.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Florian Brühlmann, Beat Vollenwyder, Klaus Opwis, and Elisa D. Mekler. 2018. Measuring the “Why” of Interaction: Development and Validation of the User Motivation Inventory (UMI). In Proceedings of the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI '18). Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA, Paper 106, 1–13. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1145/3173574.3173680">10.1145/3173574.3173680</a></p>
			<p><strong>Link: </strong><a target="_blank" href="https://osf.io/m3fbk/wiki/home/">The User Motivation Inventory (UMI)</a></p>
		</method> 

		<method id="ffmq" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,mindfulness" title="Quantitative Subjective Mindfulness: Five Facet Mindfulness Questionnaire (FFMQ)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Five Facet Mindfulness Questionnaire (FFMQ) is a questionnaire aimed at exploring the mindfulness construct and consists of 39 items that can be answered on a graduated scale (from 1 = "it never or very rarely happens to me" to 5 = "it happens to me often or always"). The FFMQ encompasses five subscales: (1) Non-react, which captures the attitude to avoid reacting to inner experiences. (2) Observe, measuring the ability to observe, notice, and look after sensations, perceptions, thoughts and feelings emerging from one's inner experience. (3) Act with awareness, a measure of the ability to act with focus and absence of distraction. (4) Describe, measuring the ability to describe and label sensations, perceptions, thoughts, and feelings emerging from one's inner experiences in words. (5) Non-judge, measuring the non-judgmental attitude towards one's inner experience.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Baer, R. A., Smith, G. T., Hopkins, J., Krietemeyer, J. and Toney, L. Using self-report assessment methods to explore facets of mindfulness. Assessment 13, 27–45 (2006). <a target="_blank" href="https://www.uv.es/friasnav/Davis_1980.pdf">PDF</a></p> 
		</method> 

		<method id="erq" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,emotions" title="Quantitative Subjective Emotions: Emotional Regulation Questionnaire (ERQ)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Emotional Regulation Questionnaire (ERQ) is a self-report questionnaire that measures an individual's typical strategies for regulating their emotional responses. The ERQ assesses two different strategies: cognitive reappraisal and expressive suppression. Cognitive reappraisal is a strategy that involves changing the way one thinks about a situation in order to regulate emotions. For example, if someone is feeling anxious about a public speaking event, they might try to reframe the situation as an opportunity for personal growth. Expressive suppression is a strategy that involves inhibiting the outward expression of emotions. For example, if someone is feeling sad, they might try to hide their emotions and appear more neutral or positive to others. The ERQ consists of items that describe different scenarios or situations, and respondents rate how frequently they use each strategy to regulate their emotions. The questionnaire has been validated and shown to have good reliability and validity in measuring these two strategies for emotion regulation.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Gouveia, V. V., Moura, H. M. D., Oliveira, I. C. V. D., Ribeiro, M. G. C., Rezende, A. T., and Brito, T. R. D. S. (2018). Emotional Regulation Questionnaire (ERQ): evidence of construct validity and internal consistency. Psico-USF, 23, 461-471. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1590/1413-82712018230306">10.1590/1413-82712018230306</a></p>  
		</method> 

		<method id="bigfive" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,personality" title="Quantitative Subjective Personality: Big Five Inventory (BFI)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Big Five Inventory (BFI) was developed by John, Donahue, and Kentle in 1991. The 44-item English BFI was constructed to allow efficient and flexible assessment of the five personality dimensions when there is no need for more differentiated measurement of individual facets. Items were selected from Big Five prototype definitions that had been developed through expert ratings and subsequent factor analytic verification in observer personality ratings. Because single trait adjectives are answered less consistently than when they are accompanied by definitions or elaborations, the BFI does not use single adjectives as items; instead, one or two prototypical trait adjectives served as the item core to which elaborative, clarifying, or contextual information was added. Thus, the BFI items are short and avoid complex sentence structures, retaining the advantages of adjectival items (brevity and simplicity) while avoiding some of their pitfalls (ambiguous or multiple meanings and salient desirability). Participants rate each BFI item on a 5-point scale ranging from 1 (disagree strongly) to 5 (agree strongly); scale scores are computed as the participant's mean item response (i.e., adding all items scored on a scale and dividing by the number of items on the scale). Despite its brevity, the BFI does not sacrifice either content coverage or good psychometric properties. (PsycTests Database Record (c) 2022 APA, all rights reserved)</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>John, O. P., Donahue, E. M., and Kentle, R. L. (1991). Big Five Inventory (BFI) [Database record]. APA PsycTests. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1037/t07550-000">10.1037/t07550-000</a></p>  
			<p><strong>Link: </strong><a target="_blank" href="https://zis.gesis.org/skala/Rammstedt-Kemper-Klein-Beierlein-Kovaleva-Big-Five-Inventory-(BFI-10)">Big Five Inventory (BFI-10)</a></p>  
		</method> 

		<method id="esq" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,emotions" title="Quantitative Subjective Emotions: Emotional State Questionnaire (ESQ)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Emotional States Questionnaire (ESQ) is a self-report questionnaire that measures an individual's emotional responses to a specific event or situation. The ESQ is used to assess emotional states such as anxiety, sadness, anger, joy, and other emotions. The questionnaire consists of a list of emotions, and respondents are asked to rate the intensity of each emotion they experienced during a particular event or situation. The ESQ has been used in various research contexts, including psychology, health sciences, and social sciences, to measure emotional responses to different events or interventions. The ESQ has been validated and shown to have good reliability and validity in measuring emotional states. The questionnaire can be modified to suit different research contexts and can be used in both clinical and non-clinical settings to assess emotional responses to specific events or situations.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Cassé-Perrot, C., Fakra, E., Jouve, E., and Blin, O. (2007). Conceptualisation and validation of the" Emotional State Questionnaire (ESQ)": evaluation of an emotional profile. L'encephale, 33(2), 169-178. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1080/10447318.2014.930312">10.1080/10447318.2014.930312</a></p>  
		</method> 

		<method id="emo" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,emotions" title="Quantitative Subjective Emotions: Emotional Metric Outcomes (EMO) Questionnaire">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Emotional Metric Outcomes (EMO) questionnaire is a new questionnaire designed to assess the emotional outcomes of interaction, especially the interaction of customers with service-provider personnel or software. The EMO is a concise multifactor standardized questionnaire that provides an assessment of transaction-driven personal and relationship emotional outcomes, both positive and negative. The primary purpose of the EMO is to move beyond traditional assessment of satisfaction to achieve a more effective measurement of customers’ emotional responses to products and processes. Psychometric evaluation showed that the EMO and its component scales had high reliability and concurrent validity with loyalty and overall experience metrics in a variety of measurement contexts. Concurrent measurement with the System Usability Scale (SUS) indicated that reported significant correlation of the SUS with likelihood-to-recommend ratings are probably primarily due to emotional rather than utilitarian aspects of the SUS.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Lewis, J. R., and Mayes, D. K. (2014). Development and psychometric evaluation of the emotional metric outcomes (EMO) questionnaire. International Journal of Human-Computer Interaction, 30(9), 685-702. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1080/10447318.2014.930312">10.1080/10447318.2014.930312</a></p>  
		</method> 

		<method id="panas" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,emotions" title="Quantitative Subjective Emotions: Positive and Negative Affect Schedule (PANAS)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Positive and Negative Affect Schedule (PANAS) is a self-report questionnaire that consists of two 10-item scales to measure both positive and negative affect. Each item is rated on a 5-point scale of 1 (not at all) to 5 (very much). The measure has been used mainly as a research tool in group studies, but can be utilized within clinical and non-clinical populations as well. Shortened, elongated, and children's versions of the PANAS have been developed, taking approximately 5–10 minutes to complete. Clinical and non-clinical studies have found the PANAS to be a reliable and valid instrument in the assessment of positive and negative affect.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Crawford, John R.; Henry, Julie D. (2004). "The Positive and Negative Affect Schedule (PANAS): Construct validity, measurement properties and normative data in a large non-clinical sample". British Journal of Clinical Psychology. 43 (3): 245–265. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1348/0144665031752934">10.1348/0144665031752934</a></p> 
			<p><strong>Link: </strong><a target="_blank" href="https://zis.gesis.org/skala/Breyer-Bluemke-Deutsche-Version-der-Positive-and-Negative-Affect-Schedule-PANAS-(GESIS-Panel)">PANAS Online (German/English)</a>, <a target="_blank" href="https://ogg.osu.edu/media/documents/MB%20Stream/PANAS.pdf">PANAS-SF</a></p>  
		</method>  

		<method id="iri" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,empathy" title="Quantitative Subjective Empathy: Interpersonal Reactivity Index (IRI)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Describes the Interpersonal Reactivity Index (IRI) and its relationships with measures of social functioning, self-esteem, emotionality, and sensitivity to others. 677 male and 667 female undergraduates served as Ss. Each of the 4 IRI subscales displayed a distinctive and predictable pattern of relationships with these measures, as well as with previous unidimensional empathy measures. Findings provide evidence for a multidimensional approach to empathy. (29 ref) (PsycINFO Database Record (c) 2019 APA, all rights reserved)</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Davis, M. H. A multidimensional approach to individual differences in empathy. Cat. Sel. Doc. Psychol. 10, 85 (1980). DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.44.1.113">10.1037/0022-3514.44.1.113</a></p> 
			<p><strong>Link: </strong><a target="_blank" href="https://www.eckerd.edu/psychology/iri/">IRI Online</a>, <a target="_blank" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interpersonal_Reactivity_Index">Wikipedia</a></p> 
		</method>  

		<method id="rses" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,selfesteem" title="Quantitative Subjective Self-Esteem: Rosenberg Self-Esteem Scale (RSES)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Rosenberg Self-Esteem Scale (RSES) was developed to measure explicit self-esteem. The scale was intended to be mono-dimensional and consists of 10 items containing 5 positive affirmations and 5 negative affirmations. Participants provide a graded response (from 1 = "strongly disagree" to 4 = "strongly agree "). The scale measures one's global self-worth and includes aspects related to self-derogation (i.e., a defence of positive self-images against any threat) and self-enhancement (i.e., rise in the eyes of others).</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Rosenberg, M. (1979). Conceiving the self. In Conceiving the self (pp. 318-318). DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2007.12.004">10.1016/j.cognition.2007.12.004</a></p> 
			<p><strong>Link: </strong><a target="_blank" href="https://zis.gesis.org/skala/Rosenberg-Self-Esteem-Scale">RSES Online</a></p> 
		</method> 

		<method id="propdrift" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,bodyownership" title="Quantitative Subjective Body-Ownership: Proprioceptive Drift">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Proprioceptive drift refers to the phenomenon in which individuals misperceive the location of their body parts after experiencing a period of sensory stimulation or deprivation. Specifically, proprioceptive drift occurs when an individual perceives their limb as being shifted away from its actual location, in the direction of a visual or tactile stimulus that was applied to the limb. Proprioceptive drift is a multimodal measure combining the processing of visual, tactile, and proprioceptive information and is based on the assumption that there is a reference description of the visual, anatomical and structural properties of the body, and that during the RHI certain multimodal brain regionsact as comparators, matching the (dummy) viewed hand with the body model reference. Modulating this comparator process has an effect on proprioceptive drift, as is evident in various experiments stimulating the brain during the RHI</p>
			<p><strong>Source (Original Work): </strong>Welch, R.B., Widawski, M.H., Harrington, J. et al. An examination of the relationship between visual capture and prism adaptation. Perception and Psychophysics 25, 126–132 (1979). DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.3758/BF03198798">10.3758/BF03198798</a></p> 
			<p><strong>Source (Rubber Hand): </strong>Tsakiris, M., and Haggard, P. (2005). The Rubber Hand Illusion Revisited: Visuotactile Integration and Self-Attribution. Journal of Experimental Psychology: Human Perception and Performance, 31(1), 80–91. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1037/0096-1523.31.1.80">10.1037/0096-1523.31.1.80</a></p> 
		</method> 

		<method id="eq" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,bodyownership" title="Quantitative Subjective Body-Ownership: Embodiment Questionnaire (EQ)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Embodiment Questionnaire (EQ) is a self-report measure developed by Manos Tsakiris and Matthew Longo in 2012 to assess people's sense of embodiment or "body ownership." The questionnaire consists of 33 items that ask participants to rate their agreement with various statements related to their experience of their own body. The EQ assesses three dimensions of embodiment: Ownership: the sense that the body is one's own and under one's control Agency: the sense of initiating and controlling movements of the body Self-location: the sense of where one's body is located in space Each item on the questionnaire is rated on a 7-point Likert scale, with higher scores indicating a stronger sense of embodiment. For example, a sample item from the questionnaire might be: "When I move my hand, I feel that the hand that I see is my own." The EQ has been used in research to study a variety of phenomena related to embodiment, including body image disorders, somatosensory processing, and multisensory integration. The questionnaire is a well-validated tool for assessing people's subjective experience of their own body, which can be useful in understanding the role of embodiment in various psychological processes and disorders.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Longo, M. R., Schüür, F., Kammers, M. P., Tsakiris, M., and Haggard, P. (2008). What is embodiment? A psychometric approach. Cognition, 107(3), 978-998. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2007.12.004">10.1016/j.cognition.2007.12.004</a></p> 
		</method> 

		<method id="veq" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,bodyownership" title="Quantitative Subjective Body-Ownership: Virtual Embodiment Questionnaire (VEQ)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Virtual Embodiment Questionnaire (VEQ) is a self-report measure designed to assess the extent to which individuals experience a sense of ownership and agency over a virtual body in a virtual environment. The VEQ consists of 12 items, which are rated on a 7-point Likert scale from strongly disagree to strongly agree. The questionnaire was developed as a tool to assess the degree of embodiment experienced in virtual reality, which refers to the feeling of being present and fully integrated into a virtual environment. Embodiment in VR is believed to be an important factor in determining the effectiveness of virtual reality experiences, particularly in applications such as virtual therapy, training simulations, and entertainment. The VEQ measures three dimensions of virtual embodiment: ownership, agency, and self-location. Ownership refers to the extent to which an individual feels that a virtual body belongs to them, agency refers to the degree to which they feel in control of the virtual body's movements and actions, and self-location refers to the feeling of being located within the virtual environment.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>D. Roth and M. E. Latoschik, "Construction of the Virtual Embodiment Questionnaire (VEQ)," in IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics, vol. 26, no. 12, pp. 3546-3556, Dec. 2020, DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1109/TVCG.2020.3023603">10.1109/TVCG.2020.3023603</a></p> 
		</method> 

		<method id="5sp" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,bodyownership" title="Quantitative Subjective Body-Ownership: Five Statements Post-Questionnaire by Banakou">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>To quantify the induced body ownership in virtual reality (VR), Banakou et al. proposes to test hypotheses based on the single-item subscales vrbody ("I felt that the virtual body I saw when looking down at myself was my own body"), mirror ("I felt that the virtual body I saw when looking at myself in the mirror was my own body"), features ("I felt that the virtual body resembled my own real body in terms of shape, skin tone or other visual features"), twobodies ("I felt as if I had two bodies"), and agency ("I felt that the movements of the virtual body were caused by my own movements") on a 7-point Likert scale from -3 (disagree) to +3 (agree).</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Banakou, D., Kishore, S., and Slater, M. (2018). Virtually being Einstein results in an improvement in cognitive task performance and a decrease in age bias. Frontiers in psychology, 9, 917. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2018.00917">10.3389/fpsyg.2018.00917</a></p> 
		</method>

		<method id="ieq" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,immersion" title="Quantitative Subjective Immersion: Immersive Experience Questionnaire for Video (Film IEQ)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Immersive Experience Questionnaire (IEQ) is a self-report measure designed to assess the subjective viewers’ experiences of immersive media. Immersion refers to the extent to which an individual feels fully engaged and absorbed in a content. The Film IEQ consists of four subscales: (1) captivation, (2) real-world dissociation, (3) comprehension, and (4) transportation. The Film IEQ allows researchers and practitioners to assess video viewing experiences using a questionnaire that is easy to administer, and that has been empirically validated.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Rigby, J. M., Brumby, D. P., Gould, S. J., and Cox, A. L. (2019, June). Development of a questionnaire to measure immersion in video media: The Film IEQ. In Proceedings of the 2019 ACM International Conference on Interactive Experiences for TV and Online Video (pp. 35-46). DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1145/3317697.3323361">10.1145/3317697.3323361</a></p> 
		</method>

		<method id="ari" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,immersion" title="Quantitative Subjective Immersion: Augmented Reality Immersion (ARI)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Augmented Reality Immersion (ARI) questionnaire is a self-report measure designed to assess the level of immersion experienced by individuals during an augmented reality (AR) experience. The questionnaire consists of items that ask participants to rate their subjective experience to AR immersion on a Likert scale. The ARI questionnaire was developed as a tool to assess the effectiveness of AR experiences and to help developers and researchers identify areas for improvement in AR design. The questionnaire includes items that assess the sensory, cognitive, and emotional components of ARI, such as the level of engagement, the sense of being physically present in the AR environment, and the feeling of having control over the AR experience. This multi-step process resulted in a 21-item, seven-point Likert-type instrument.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Georgiou, Y., and Kyza, E. A. (2017). The development and validation of the ARI questionnaire: An instrument for measuring immersion in location-based augmented reality settings. International Journal of Human-Computer Studies, 98, 24-37. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhcs.2016.09.014">10.1016/j.ijhcs.2016.09.014</a></p> 
		</method>

		<method id="wspq" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,presence" title="Quantitative Subjective Presence: Witmer-Singer Presence Questionnaire (PQ)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Witmer-Singer Presence Questionnaire (PQ) is one of the first self-report measures designed to assess the degree of presence experienced by individuals in virtual environments. Presence is defined as the subjective experience of being in a virtual environment despite physical separation from the real world. The PQ consists of 32 items that are rated on a 7-point Likert scale, with higher scores indicating a greater sense of presence. The items cover a range of factors that contribute to presence, such as the sensory realism of the virtual environment, the level of attention and engagement, and the feeling of control over the virtual environment. The PQ was developed by researchers Thomas Witmer and Janice Singer in 1998 and has since been widely used in virtual reality (VR) research to assess the effectiveness of VR applications and to identify ways to improve the user experience. The questionnaire has been shown to have good psychometric properties, including high reliability and validity, and has been translated into several languages. Overall, the PQ provides a standardized and validated method for measuring presence in virtual environments, which can help researchers and developers better understand and optimize the user experience in VR applications.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Witmer, B. G., and Singer, M. J. (1998). Measuring presence in virtual environments: A presence questionnaire. Presence, 7(3), 225-240. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1162/105474698565686">10.1162/105474698565686</a></p>  
			<p><strong>Download: </strong><a target="_blank" href="https://apps.dtic.mil/sti/pdfs/ADA286183.pdf">Witmer-Singer Presence Questionnaire (v 2.0)</a> (p. 49)</p>  
		</method>

		<method id="itq" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,presence" title="Quantitative Subjective Presence: Immersive Tendencies Questionnaire (ITQ)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Immersive Tendencies Questionnaire (ITQ) is a self-report measure designed to assess an individual's tendency to become fully engaged and absorbed in immersive experiences, such as virtual reality (VR), video games, and movies. The ITQ consists of 29 items, which are rated on a 7-point Likert scale ranging from strongly disagree to strongly agree. The ITQ was developed to identify individual differences in the way people engage with and respond to immersive experiences, with the goal of better understanding the psychological and behavioral factors that contribute to immersive tendencies. The questionnaire covers a range of dimensions, including attentional focus, emotional involvement, and absorption in the experience. The ITQ has been shown to have good psychometric properties, including high reliability and validity, and has been used in research to investigate the impact of immersive technologies on cognitive and emotional processes, as well as to identify factors that may influence individual differences in immersive tendencies.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Witmer, B. G., and Singer, M. J. (1998). Measuring presence in virtual environments: A presence questionnaire. Presence, 7(3), 225-240. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1162/105474698565686">10.1162/105474698565686</a></p>  
			<p><strong>Download: </strong><a target="_blank" href="https://apps.dtic.mil/sti/pdfs/ADA286183.pdf">Witmer-Singer Immersive Tendencies Questionnaire (v 2.0)</a> (p. 44)</p>  
		</method>

		<method id="ipq" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,presence" title="Quantitative Subjective Presence: iGroup Presence Questionnaire (IPQ)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The iGroup Presence Questionnaire (IPQ) is a self-report measure designed to assess the subjective experience of presence in a virtual environment, specifically in the context of social interaction. Presence refers to the feeling of being present in a virtual environment as if it were real, and it is considered an important factor in determining the effectiveness of social interactions in virtual reality. It is a 14-item scale for measuring the sense of presence experienced in a virtual environment (VE). It was constructed using a large pool of items and two survey waves with approximately 500 participants. The scale has four subscales: General Presence, Spatial Presence, Involvement, and Experienced Realism.</p> 
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Regenbrecht, H., and Schubert, T. (2002). Real and illusory interaction enhance presence in virtual environments. Presence: Teleoperators and Virtual Environments, 11(4), 425-434. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1162/105474602760204318">10.1162/105474602760204318</a></p>  
			<p><strong>Download: </strong><a target="_blank" href="http://www.igroup.org/pq/ipq/download.php">iGroup Presence Questionnaire (IPQ) Item Download</a></p>  
		</method>

		<method id="quis" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,usability,satisfaction" title="Quantitative Subjective Usability: Questionnaire for User Interface Satisfaction (QUIS)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Questionnaire for User Interface Satisfaction (QUIS) is a self-report measure designed to assess user satisfaction with a computer-based interface. The QUIS was developed by a team of researchers at the University of Maryland in the early 1990s and has been widely used in research and industry to evaluate the usability and user experience of software applications. The QUIS consists of 27 items, which are rated on a 9-point Likert scale. The questionnaire measures user satisfaction across four dimensions: overall reaction, screen, terminology and system feedback, learning factors, and system capabilities.</p> 
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>John P. Chin, Virginia A. Diehl, and Kent L. Norman. 1988. Development of an instrument measuring user satisfaction of the human-computer interface. In Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI '88). Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA, 213–218. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1145/57167.57203">10.1145/57167.57203</a></p>   
		</method> 

		<method id="attrakdiff" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,usability" title="Quantitative Subjective Usability: Pragmatic and Hedonic Qualities (AttrakDiff/AttrakDiff Mini)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The AttrakDiff questionnaire is a self-report measure designed to assess the perceived hedonic and pragmatic quality of a product, service, or system. The questionnaire was developed by Marc Hassenzahl and colleagues in 2003 and has been widely used in research and industry to evaluate the user experience of various products and systems. The AttrakDiff questionnaire consists of 28 bipolar items, which are rated on a 7-point Likert scale from "not at all" to "very much." The questionnaire measures the perceived hedonic quality (attractiveness, stimulation, and identification) and pragmatic quality (usability, clarity, and efficiency) of the product, service, or system. The perceived hedonic quality of a product refers to its emotional appeal, aesthetics, and the degree to which it satisfies the user's personal preferences and values. The perceived pragmatic quality, on the other hand, refers to its functional aspects, including ease of use, efficiency, and effectiveness. The AttrakDiff questionnaire provides a standardized and validated method for assessing the perceived quality of a product, service, or system, which can help researchers and developers better understand and optimize the user experience. By measuring both the hedonic and pragmatic aspects of the user experience, the AttrakDiff questionnaire can provide a more comprehensive understanding of the factors that influence user satisfaction and acceptance of a product or system.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Hassenzahl, M., Burmester, M., and Koller, F. (2003). AttrakDiff: Ein Fragebogen zur Messung wahrgenommener hedonischer und pragmatischer Qualität. Mensch und Computer 2003: Interaktion in Bewegung, 187-196.</p>
			<p><strong>Download: </strong><a target="_blank" href="https://hci-studies.org/methods-and-measures/downloads/AttrakDiff_German.pdf">AttrakDiff/AttrakDiff Mini (German)</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="ueq" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,usability" title="Quantitative Subjective Usability: User Experience Questionnaire (UEQ)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The User Experience Questionnaire (UEQ) is a self-report measure designed to assess the overall user experience of a product or system. Usually 3 to 5 minutes are sufficient for a participant to read the instructions and complete the questionnaire. The questionnaire was developed in 2008 and has been widely used in research and industry to evaluate the usability and user experience of various products and systems. The UEQ consists of 26 items, which are rated on a 7-point Likert scale. The questionnaire measures six dimensions of the user experience: attractiveness, perspicuity, efficiency, dependability, stimulation, and novelty. The short version, UEQ-S, only supports the scales hedonic quality and pragmatic quality. The UEQ is currently available in 17 languages (German, English, French, Italian, Russian, Spanish, Portuguese, Turkish, Chinese, Japanese, Indonesian, Dutch, Estonian, Slovene, Swedish, Greek, and Polish). The UEQ can be used either in paper-and-pencil form or as an online questionnaire.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Laugwitz, B., Schrepp, M. and Held, T. (2008). Construction and evaluation of a user experience questionnaire. In: Holzinger, A. (Ed.): USAB 2008, LNCS 5298, pp. 63-76. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-540-89350-9_6">10.1007/978-3-540-89350-9_6</a></p>
			<p><strong>Link: </strong><a target="_blank" href="https://www.ueq-online.org/">UEQ Online</a></p> 
		</method>

		<method id="umux" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,usability" title="Quantitative Subjective Usability: Usability Metric for User Experience (UMUX)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Usability Metric for User Experience (UMUX) is a four-item scale used for the subjective assessment of an application’s perceived usability. It is designed to provide results similar to those obtained with the 10-item System Usability Scale, and is organized around the ISO 9241-11 definition of usability. A pilot version was assembled from candidate items, which was then tested alongside the System Usability Scale during usability testing. It was shown that the two scales correlate well, are reliable, and both align on one underlying usability factor. In addition, the Usability Metric for User Experience is compact enough to serve as a usability module in a broader user experience metric.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Finstad, K. (2010). The usability metric for user experience. Interacting with computers, 22(5), 323-327. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.intcom.2010.04.004">10.1016/j.intcom.2010.04.004</a></p>
			<p><strong>Download: </strong><a target="_blank" href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Kraig-Finstad/publication/220054775_The_Usability_Metric_for_User_Experience/links/5c5083aa299bf12be3eba206/The-Usability-Metric-for-User-Experience.pdf">Usability Metric for User Experience (UMUX)</a></p> 
		</method>

		<method id="usabilitysus" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,usability" title="Quantitative Subjective Usability: System Usability Scale (SUS)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The System Usability Scale (SUS) provides a "quick and dirty" but reliable tool for measuring usability. It consists of a 10-item questionnaire with five response options ranging from Strongly agree to Strongly disagree. Originally created by John Brooke in 1986, it allows you to evaluate a wide variety of products and services, including hardware, software, mobile devices, websites, and applications.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Brooke, J. (1996). "SUS: a "quick and dirty" usability scale". In P. W. Jordan; B. Thomas; B. A. Weerdmeester; A. L. McClelland (eds.). Usability Evaluation in Industry. London: Taylor and Francis.</p>
			<p><strong>Download: </strong><a href="https://stuart-cunningham.github.io/sus/" target='_blank'>SUS Score Calculator</a>, <a target="_blank" href="https://hci-studies.org/methods-and-measures/downloads/SUS.pdf">Download</a>, <a target="_blank" href="https://hci-studies.org/methods-and-measures/downloads/SUS_Brooke1996.pdf">Download with Instructions</a></p> 
			<p><strong>Link: </strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System_usability_scale" target='_blank'>Wikipedia</a></p>  
		</method>

		<method id="nasatlx" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,workload,randomsample" title="Quantitative Subjective Cognitive Load: NASA Task Load Index (NASA-TLX)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The NASA Task Load Index (NASA-TLX) is a widely used, subjective, multidimensional assessment tool that rates perceived workload in order to assess a task, system, or team's effectiveness or other aspects of performance. There is a weighted (TLX) and raw version (RTLX) assessing mental demand, physical demand, temporal demand, performance, effort, and frustration.</p> 
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Hart, Sandra G.; Staveland, Lowell E. (1988). Development of NASA-TLX (Task Load Index): Results of Empirical and Theoretical Research. In Hancock, Peter A.; Meshkati, Najmedin (eds.). Human Mental Workload. Advances in Psychology. Vol. 52. Amsterdam: North Holland. pp. 139–183. <a target='_blank' href="http://usd-apps.usd.edu/coglab/schieber/psyc792/workload/Hart-Staveland-1988.pdf">DOI:10.1016/S0166-4115(08)62386-9</a>.</p>
			<p><strong>Follow-Up Source: </strong>Hart, Sandra G. (October 2006). NASA-task load index (NASA-TLX); 20 years later. In Proceedings of the human factors and ergonomics society annual meeting (Vol. 50, No. 9, pp. 904-908). Sage CA: Los Angeles, CA: Sage publications. DOI:<a href='https://humansystems.arc.nasa.gov/groups/TLX/downloads/HFES_2006_Paper.pdf' target='_blank'>10.1016/S0166-4115(08)62386-9</a>.</p>
			<p><strong>Downloads: </strong><a target='_blank' href="https://humansystems.arc.nasa.gov/groups/tlx/downloads/TLXScale.pdf">PDF</a>, <a target='_blank' href="https://www.keithv.com/software/nasatlx/">Online Version</a>, <a target='_blank' href="https://humansystems.arc.nasa.gov/groups/tlx/tlxapp.php">Apps for iOS and Android</a>
			</p> 
			<p><strong>Link: </strong><a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NASA-TLX' target='_blank'>Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="geq" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,games,randomsample" title="Quantitative Subjective Gaming Experience: Game Experience Questionnaire (GEQ)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Game Experience Questionnaire has a modular structure and consists of: 1. the core questionnaire, 2. the Social Presence Module, and 3. the Post-game Module. In addition to these modules, a concise in-game version of the GEQ was developed. All three modules are meant to be administered immediately after the game session has finished, in the order given above. Parts one and two probe the players' feelings and thoughts while playing the game; part three, the post-game module, assesses how players felt after they had stopped playing.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>IJsselsteijn, W. A., de Kort, Y. A. W., and Poels, K. (2013). The Game Experience Questionnaire. Technische Universiteit Eindhoven. <a href="https://research.tue.nl/en/publications/the-game-experience-questionnaire" target='_blank'>PDF</a></p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Law, E. L. C., Brühlmann, F., and Mekler, E. D. (2018, October). Systematic review and validation of the game experience questionnaire (geq)-implications for citation and reporting practice. In Proceedings of the 2018 Annual Symposium on Computer-Human Interaction in Play (pp. 257-270). <a href="https://doi.org/10.1145/3242671.3242683" target='_blank'>10.1145/3242671.3242683</a></p>
		</method>   

		<method id="guess" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,games,randomsample" title="Quantitative Subjective Gaming Experience: Game User Experience Satisfaction Scale (GUESS)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Game User Experience Satisfaction Scale (GUESS) is a validated instrument designed to assess video game satisfaction across multiple dimensions crucial to the gaming experience. Developed to address the inadequacies of existing evaluation tools in capturing comprehensive feedback during playtesting and game evaluation, GUESS employs a psychometrically robust framework based on extensive research and methodology best practices. It consists of nine subscales including aspects like usability, playability, narratives, play engrossment, enjoyment, creative freedom, audio and visual aesthetics, personal gratification, and social connectivity. These factors collectively measure a game's ability to deliver a satisfying user experience, making GUESS applicable across various genres and platforms in the gaming industry. The scale's development involved a mixed-method approach, including item pool generation, expert review, pilot testing, exploratory and confirmatory factor analysis, ensuring its reliability and validity in assessing the multidimensional construct of game satisfaction.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Phan, M., Keebler, J., and Chaparro, B. (2016). The Development and Validation of the Game User Experience Satisfaction Scale (GUESS). Human Factors: The Journal of the Human Factors and Ergonomics Society, 58. doi: <a href="https://doi.org/10.1177/0018720816669646" target='_blank'>10.1177/0018720816669646</a></p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Joseph R. Keebler, William J. Shelstad, Dustin C. Smith, Barbara S. Chaparro, and Mikki H. Phan. 2020. Validation of the GUESS-18: A Short Version of the Game User Experience Satisfaction Scale (GUESS). J. Usability Studies 16, 1 (nov 2020), 49–62.</p>
		</method>  

		<method id="pxi" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,games,randomsample" title="Quantitative Subjective Gaming Experience: The Player Experience Inventory (PXI, miniPXI)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Player Experience Inventory (PXI) is a validated, theoretically grounded tool designed for Games User Research that measures both immediate functional consequences and broader psychosocial emotional responses to provide actionable insights into how specific design choices shape player experience.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Vanden Abeele, V., Spiel, K., Nacke, L., Johnson, D., Gerling, K. (2020). Development and validation of the player experience inventory: A scale to measure player experiences at the level of functional and psychosocial consequences. International Journal of Human-Computer Studies, 135, 102370. doi: <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhcs.2019.102370" target='_blank'>10.1016/j.ijhcs.2019.102370</a></p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Aqeel Haider, Casper Harteveld, Daniel Johnson, Max V. Birk, Regan L. Mandryk, Magy Seif El-Nasr, Lennart E. Nacke, Kathrin Gerling, and Vero Vanden Abeele. 2022. MiniPXI: Development and Validation of an Eleven-Item Measure of the Player Experience Inventory. Proc. ACM Hum.-Comput. Interact. 6, CHI PLAY, Article 244 (October 2022), doi: <a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3549507" target='_blank'>10.1145/3549507</a></p>
		</method>  

		<method id="hexad" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,games,randomsample" title="Quantitative Subjective Gaming Experience: Gamification User Types Hexad Scale">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Hexad model is a framework used in gamification to align game design elements with user personality traits, aiming to personalize user experiences more effectively. It categorizes users into six types based on their motivations and interactions with gamified systems. These types are Achievers, Philanthropists, Socializers, Free Spirits, Players, and Disruptors. Each type responds differently to gamified elements, like challenges or social engagement features. Recognizing the challenge of directly assessing user preferences within these categories, researchers developed a 24-item Hexad scale to measure individual inclination towards these six motivations. This scale has undergone various validations, including internal consistency and factor analysis, to ensure its reliability and accuracy. It also correlates these user types with the Big Five personality traits, providing a robust tool for understanding user behavior in gamified systems. However, concerns about the length of the 24-item questionnaire potentially leading to participant dropout and fatigue prompted the creation of a condensed 12-item version of the Hexad scale. This shorter version retains the integrity of the original while enhancing usability and reducing participant burden. It has been validated through factor analyses and shows improved model fit and reliability. This makes the Hexad-12 an effective and efficient tool for deploying tailored gamification strategies in UX design, particularly when included in larger surveys where brevity and participant engagement are crucial.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Tondello, G. F., Wehbe, R. R., Diamond, L., Busch, M., Marczewski, A., and Nacke, L. E. (2016). The Gamification User Types Hexad Scale. CHI PLAY '16: Proceedings of the 2016 Annual Symposium on Computer-Human Interaction in Play. Association for Computing Machinery. doi: <a href="https://doi.org/10.1145/2967934.2968082" target='_blank'>10.1145/2967934.2968082</a></p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Jeanine Krath, Maximilian Altmeyer, Gustavo F. Tondello, and Lennart E. Nacke. 2023. Hexad-12: Developing and Validating a Short Version of the Gamification User Types Hexad Scale. In Proceedings of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA, Article 677, 18 pages. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1145/3544548.3580968" target='_blank'>10.1145/3544548.3580968</a></p>
		</method> 

		<method id="PENS" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,games,randomsample" title="Quantitative Subjective Gaming Experience: Player Experience of Need Satisfaction (PENS)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Player Experience of Need Satisfaction (PENS) is a questionnaire grounded in Self-Determination Theory for assessing how strongly a game supports psychological needs such as competence, autonomy, and relatedness. In games user research, it is useful when the goal is to understand motivational quality, need satisfaction, and the experiential foundations of player engagement.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Johnson, D., Gardner, M. J., and Perry, R. (2018). Validation of two game experience scales: The Player Experience of Need Satisfaction (PENS) and Game Experience Questionnaire (GEQ). Int. J. Hum. Comput. Stud., 118, 38–46. doi:  <a href="https://pdf.sciencedirectassets.com/272548/1-s2.0-S1071581918X00081/1-s2.0-S1071581918302337/main.pdf?" target='_blank'>10.1007/s11257-019-09223-w</a></p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Ryan, R. M., Rigby, C. S., and Przybylski, A. (2006). The Motivational Pull of Video Games: A Self-Determination Theory Approach. Motiv. Emot., 30(4), 344–360. doi: <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11031-006-9051-8" target='_blank'> 10.1007/s11031-006-9051-8</a></p>
		</method>
		
		<method id="VGDFS" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,flow,randomsample" title="Quantitative Subjective Gaming Experience: The Video Game Dispositional Flow Scale (VGDFS)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Video Game Dispositional Flow Scale (VGDFS) is a 28-item psychometric instrument developed and validated through a multi-phase study to accurately measure the dispositional flow experience of adult players by utilizing a hierarchical antecedent model that addresses previous conceptual and empirical flaws.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Cai, X., Cebollada, J., Cortiñas, M. (2022). Self-report measure of dispositional flow experience in the video game context: Conceptualisation and scale development. International Journal of Human-Computer Studies, 159, 102746. doi:  <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhcs.2021.102746" target='_blank'>10.1016/j.ijhcs.2021.102746</a></p>
		</method>
		
		<method id="gamefulquest" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,games,randomsample" title="Quantitative Subjective Gaming Experience: The Gameful Experience Questionnaire (GAMEFULQUEST)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>GAMEFULQUEST is a validated, multi-dimensional instrument developed to measure a user's gameful experience within gamified systems and services, providing a standardized way to evaluate how effectively a design evokes game-like motivations and behaviors for user-adapted gamification.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Högberg, J., Hamari, J., Wästlund, E. (2019). Gameful Experience Questionnaire (GAMEFULQUEST): An instrument for measuring the perceived gamefulness of system use. User Modeling and User-Adapted Interaction, 29(3), 619-660. doi: <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11257-019-09223-w" target='_blank'>10.1007/s11257-019-09223-w</a></p>
		</method>
		
		<method id="gameengagementquestionnaire" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,games,randomsample" title="Quantitative Subjective Gaming Experience: Game Engagement Questionnaire (Engagement GEQ)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Game Engagement Questionnaire (GEQ) is a psychometrically validated tool developed using classical and Rasch analyses to measure the subjective levels of deep engagement in video game-playing, specifically to explore its role as a determinant of the impact of violent video games.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Brockmyer, J. H., Fox, C. M., Curtiss, K. A., McBroom, E., Burkhart, K. M., Pidruzny, J. N. (2009). The development of the Game Engagement Questionnaire: A measure of engagement in video game-playing. Journal of experimental social psychology, 45(4), 624-634. doi:  <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jesp.2009.02.016" target='_blank'>10.1016/j.jesp.2009.02.016</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="errorrate" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,performance,randomsample" title="Quantitative Objective Performance: Input Error Rate (%)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Input error rate is a measure of the frequency with which a user makes errors while interacting with a computer system or interface. It is a commonly used metric in human-computer interaction (HCI) research and usability testing, as errors can have a significant impact on user performance, efficiency, and satisfaction. Input error rate can be measured in a variety of ways, depending on the specific task and interface being evaluated. For example, it may be measured as the percentage of keystrokes that result in an incorrect character being entered, or the percentage of clicks or taps that are made in the wrong location on a screen. Input error rate can be affected by a range of factors, including the complexity of the task, the design and layout of the interface, the user's level of experience and familiarity with the system, and the type and sensitivity of the input device being used. By tracking input error rate and analyzing any patterns or trends that emerge, designers and researchers can identify areas where users may be encountering difficulties or confusion, and make informed decisions about how to improve interface designs and optimize task performance.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technique_for_human_error-rate_prediction' target='_blank'>Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="accuarcy" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,performance,randomsample" title="Quantitative Objective Performance: Pointing Accuracy/Precision">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Pointing accuracy and pointing precision are two related but distinct measures of how accurately a user can point to a target on a computer screen using a pointing device such as a mouse or touchpad. Pointing accuracy, also known as target offset, is a measure of how close the user's pointing device clicks or taps are to the center of the target. Target offset is typically calculated by measuring the distance between the center of the target and the location where the user actually clicked or tapped. Pointing precision, on the other hand, is a measure of how consistently the user can point to the same location on the screen over multiple attempts. It is calculated by measuring the variance or standard deviation of the user's clicks or taps relative to the center of the target. Both pointing accuracy and precision are important usability metrics for evaluating the effectiveness of pointing devices and interface designs. A pointing device with high accuracy but low precision may be frustrating to use, as the user is unable to consistently click on the same location. Conversely, a pointing device with high precision but low accuracy may also be frustrating, as the user may have to repeatedly adjust their aim to hit the target. In HCI research, pointing accuracy and precision are often used in conjunction with other metrics such as task completion time and user satisfaction to provide a comprehensive evaluation of interface design and usability.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision' target='_blank'>Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method> 

		<method id="textentry" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,performance,randomsample" title="Quantitative Objective Performance: Text Input Speed in Words per Minute (WPM)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Text input speed in words per minute (WPM) is a measure of how quickly a person can type text on a keyboard or other input device. It is a commonly used metric to assess a person's typing proficiency and speed. To measure text input speed, a person is typically given a text passage to type, and their speed is measured by the number of words they can accurately type within a set time period, usually one minute. For example, if a person types 80 words correctly in one minute, their text input speed would be 80 WPM. Text input speed can be affected by a range of factors, including typing technique, keyboard layout, familiarity with the text passage, and level of experience with typing. In the context of human-computer interaction, text input speed is an important consideration for designing interfaces and evaluating the usability of input devices. In evaluations of text entry methods, participants enter phrases of text using a technique of interest while performance data are collected. A phrase set by MacKenzie and Soukoreff describes and publishes a collection of 500 phrases for such evaluations. Utility programs are also provided to compute statistical properties of the phrase set, or any other phrase set. The merits of using a pre-defined phrase set are described as are methodological considerations, such as attaining results that are generalizable and the possible addition of punctuation and other characters</p>
			<p><strong>Source:</strong> I. Scott MacKenzie and R. William Soukoreff. 2003. Phrase sets for evaluating text entry techniques. In CHI '03 Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI EA '03). Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA, 754–755. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1145/765891.765971" target='_blank'>https://doi.org/10.1145/765891.765971</a></p>
			<p><strong>Download:</strong> <a href="http://www.yorku.ca/mack/PhraseSets.zip" target='_blank'>Phrase Sets for Evaluating Text Entry Techniques</a></p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://10fastfingers.com/" target='_blank'>10 Fast Fingers</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="sentiment" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,textanalysis,randomsample" title="Quantitative Objective Text Metric: Sentiment Analysis">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Sentiment analysis, also known as opinion mining, is a field of study that analyzes people's opinions, sentiments, evaluations, attitudes, and emotions from written language. It is a prevalent tool in the processing of natural language, helping to ascertain the contextual polarity of textual material, whether the expressed opinion in documents, tweets, and other social media is positive, negative, or neutral. Applications of sentiment analysis are broad and highly useful in business environments. Companies use it to understand consumer sentiment toward products, brand reputation, and service quality by analyzing data from social media, survey responses, or online reviews. The technique often involves machine learning algorithms or lexicon-based approaches to classify the sentiment of texts. In machine learning-based approaches, text data is usually converted into a format that can be fed into algorithms (like support vector machines, neural networks, or deep learning models) that classify the sentiment. The model learns from a pre-labeled dataset in a supervised learning setting to recognize sentiment in new inputs. In contrast, lexicon-based approaches involve calculating sentiment scores based on the presence of predefined words associated with positive or negative sentiments.</p>
			<p><strong>Source:</strong> Liu, B. (2012). Sentiment Analysis and Opinion Mining. Morgan and Claypool Publishers</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis" target='_blank'>Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="lexicaldiversity" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,textanalysis,randomsample" title="Quantitative Objective Text Metric: Lexical Diversity Analysis">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Lexical diversity measures the range of different words used in a text, providing insights into the vocabulary richness and usage variety within a document. It is often quantified using metrics such as the Type-Token Ratio (TTR), which calculates the ratio of unique words (types) to the total number of words (tokens) in a text. This analysis helps in assessing the linguistic complexity and the style of writing, important in educational settings, authorship attribution, and language studies.</p>
   			<p><strong>Source:</strong> McCarthy, P. M., and Jarvis, S. (2010). MTLD, vocd-D, and HD-D: A validation study of sophisticated approaches to lexical diversity assessment. Behavior Research Methods, 42(2), 381-392.</p>
    		<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.3758/BRM.42.2.381" target='_blank'>Springer Link</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="coherence" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,textanalysis,randomsample" title="Quantitative Objective Text Metric: Coherence Analysis">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Text coherence refers to the logical and semantic connection between different parts of a text, which makes the content easy to understand and follow. Coherence is assessed through the use of various linguistic devices like transitional phrases, pronoun reference, and theme development. Analyzing coherence is crucial in educational evaluations, automated essay scoring, and any application where the flow of text impacts its comprehensibility and effectiveness.</p>
			<p><strong>Source:</strong> Graesser, A. C., McNamara, D. S., Louwerse, M. M., and Cai, Z. (2004). Coh-Metrix: Analysis of text on cohesion and language. Behavioral Research Methods, Instruments, and Computers, 36(2), 193-202.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.3758/BF03195564" target='_blank'>Springer Link</a></p>
		</method> 

		<method id="lda" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,textanalysis,randomsample" title="Quantitative Objective Text Metric: Latent Dirichlet Allocation (LDA)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Latent Dirichlet Allocation (LDA) is a generative statistical model that allows sets of observations to be explained by unobserved groups, helping to understand why some parts of the data are similar. In text analysis, LDA is used to classify text in a document to a particular topic, enabling the discovery of topic distribution across a corpus. This technique is widely used in digital humanities, content analysis, and information retrieval to enhance the accuracy of document classification.</p>
			<p><strong>Source:</strong> Blei, D. M., Ng, A. Y., and Jordan, M. I. (2003). Latent dirichlet allocation. The Journal of Machine Learning Research, 3, 993-1022.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://www.jmlr.org/papers/volume3/blei03a/blei03a.pdf" target='_blank'>Journal of Machine Learning Research</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="readability" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,textanalysis,randomsample" title="Quantitative Objective Text Metric: Readability Scores">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Readability scores assess the ease with which a reader can understand a written text. The Flesch-Kincaid Reading Ease, Gunning Fog Index, and SMOG Index are common formulas used to estimate the readability. These scores consider factors like sentence length and word difficulty to provide a grade level necessary to comprehend the text. Readability is crucial in educational content development, legal documents, and healthcare communications to ensure accessibility and comprehensibility.</p>
			<p><strong>Source:</strong> Kincaid, J. P., Fishburne, R. P., Rogers, R. L., and Chissom, B. S. (1975). Derivation of new readability formulas (Automated Readability Index, Fog Count and Flesch Reading Ease Formula) for Navy enlisted personnel. Research Branch Report 8-75, Naval Technical Training, U. S. Naval Air Station, Memphis, TN.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://stars.library.ucf.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1055" target='_blank'>Defense Technical Information Center</a></p>
		</method>
		
		<method id="tfidf" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,textanalysis,randomsample" title="Quantitative Objective Text Metric: Term Frequency-Inverse Document Frequency (TF-IDF)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Term Frequency-Inverse Document Frequency (TF-IDF) is a statistical measure used to evaluate how important a word is to a document in a collection or corpus. The importance increases proportionally to the number of times a word appears in the document but is offset by the frequency of the word in the corpus. TF-IDF is often used in text mining and information retrieval to weight terms during document retrieval and indexing.</p>
			<p><strong>Source:</strong> Salton, G., and McGill, M. J. (1983). Introduction to Modern Information Retrieval. McGraw-Hill, Inc.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tf%E2%80%93idf" target='_blank'>Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="frequency" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,textanalysis,randomsample" title="Quantitative Objective Text Metric: Frequency Counts">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Frequency counts involve tallying the occurrences of words, phrases, or characters in a text. This simple yet powerful analytical tool is essential for identifying the most frequently used terms within a text, helping in keyword analysis, thematic studies, and understanding linguistic habits. Frequency counts are fundamental in computational linguistics, content analysis, and natural language processing.</p>
			<p><strong>Source:</strong> Manning, C. D., and Schütze, H. (1999). Foundations of Statistical Natural Language Processing. MIT Press.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://nlp.stanford.edu/fsnlp/" target='_blank'>Stanford NLP</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="nps" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,satisfaction" title="Quantitative Subjective Satisfaction: Net Promoter Score (NPS)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Net Promoter Score is calculated based on responses to a single question: "On a scale from 0 to 10, how likely are you to recommend our company/product/service/system/prototype/method to a friend or colleague?" Based on their ratings, respondents are categorized into three segments:</p>
			<p><strong>1. Promoters (score 9-10):</strong> These are highly satisfied customers who are likely to engage in positive word-of-mouth activities, including recommending the product or service to others.</p>
			<p><strong>2. Passives (score 7-8):</strong> Satisfied but unenthusiastic customers who are vulnerable to competitive offerings.</p>
			<p><strong>3. Detractors (score 0-6):</strong> Unsatisfied customers who could potentially damage the brand and impede growth through negative word-of-mouth.</p>
			<p>The NPS is derived by subtracting the percentage of Detractors from the percentage of Promoters. The score itself can range from -100 (if every customer is a Detractor) to 100 (if every customer is a Promoter). NPS is revered for its simplicity and its strong correlation with a company's growth and customer loyalty levels. A higher NPS indicates more Promoters relative to Detractors, which often correlates with better overall business performance. Companies utilize NPS to identify strengths and weaknesses in customer service and product offerings and to motivate an organization towards customer-centric improvement. However, NPS has its critics who argue that it oversimplifies customer experiences by boiling them down to a single metric, potentially ignoring other important aspects of customer satisfaction and loyalty. Furthermore, NPS does not differentiate between the passivity of different demographic groups or market segments, which could lead to misinterpretations.</p>
			<p><strong>Source:</strong>Frederick F. Reichheld: The number one you need to grow. In: Harvard Business Review</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href="https://www.qualtrics.com/experience-management/customer/net-promoter-score/" target='_blank'>NPS - The Ultimate Guide</a></p>
		</method> 
		
		<method id="fittslaw" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,performance,randomsample" title="Quantitative Objective Performance: Fitts' Law (Throughput)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Fitts' law states that the amount of time required for a person to move a pointer (e.g., mouse cursor) to a target area is a function of the distance to the target divided by the size of the target. Thus, the longer the distance and the smaller the target's size, the longer it takes. According to Fitts' law, human movement can be modeled by analogy to the transmission of information denoted as throughput in bits/s. Fitts' popular model has been widely adopted in numerous research areas, including kinematics, human factors, and human-computer interaction (HCI).</p>
			<p><strong>1D Fitts' law task:</strong> MacKenzie, I. S. (1992). Fitts' law as a research and design tool in human-computer interaction. Human-computer interaction, 7(1), 91-139. DOI: <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1207/s15327051hci0701_3" target='_blank'>https://doi.org/10.1207/s15327051hci0701_3</a></p>
			<p><strong>2D Fitts' law task:</strong> MacKenzie, I. S., and Buxton, W. (1992, June). Extending Fitts' law to two-dimensional tasks. In Proceedings of the SIGCHI conference on Human factors in computing systems (pp. 219-226). <a href='https://doi.org/10.1145/142750.142794' target='_blank'>https://doi.org/10.1145/142750.142794</a></p>
			<p><strong>3D Fitts' law task:</strong> Cha, Y., and Myung, R. (2013). Extended Fitts' law for 3D pointing tasks using 3D target arrangements. International Journal of Industrial Ergonomics, 43(4), 350-355. <a href='https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ergon.2013.05.005' target='_blank'>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ergon.2013.05.005</a></p>
			<p><strong>Link: </strong><a href='http://www.yorku.ca/mack/FittsLawSoftware/' target='_blank'>Fitts' Law Software Download</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="stroop" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,memory,randomsample" title="Quantitative Objective Memory: Stroop Test">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Stroop test is a classic neuropsychological task that is widely used to assess memory attention, cognitive flexibility, and processing speed. The test was developed by J.R. Stroop in 1935 and has been used in research and clinical settings to evaluate executive functioning, brain injury, and various cognitive disorders. In the standard version of the Stroop test, participants are presented with a list of words that are printed in colored ink. The task is to name the color of the ink as quickly and accurately as possible. The test consists of three parts: In the first part, the words are all printed in black ink, and participants are asked to read the words as quickly as possible. In the second part, the words are printed in different colors, but the color of the ink and the word meaning are the same. For example, the word "red" might be printed in red ink. Participants are again asked to name the color of the ink. In the third part, the words are printed in different colors, and the color of the ink and the word meaning are different. For example, the word "red" might be printed in blue ink. Participants are asked to name the color of the ink as quickly and accurately as possible. The Stroop effect occurs when the word meaning interferes with the naming of the ink color, resulting in slower reaction times and increased errors in the third part of the test. This interference is thought to reflect the automatic processing of word meanings and the need for cognitive control to overcome this interference and focus on the task-relevant information (i.e., the color of the ink). The Stroop test is a widely used and well-established measure of attentional control and cognitive flexibility. It is used in both research and clinical settings to assess various cognitive disorders such as attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD), Alzheimer's disease, and traumatic brain injury.</p>
			<p><strong>Source:</strong> Kirchner, W. K. (1958). Age differences in short-term retention of rapidly changing information. Journal of Experimental Psychology, 55(4), 352–358. <a href="https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1037/h0054651" target='_blank'>10.1207/s15327051hci0701_3</a></p>
			<p><strong>Link</strong> <a href='https://psynet.ruhr-uni-bochum.de/cognition/stroop/intro/index.htm' target='_blank'>Stroop-Test Online</a>, <a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_to_completion' target='_blank'>Wikipedia</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="nback" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,memory,randomsample" title="Quantitative Objective Memory: N-back Task">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The n-back task is a widely used cognitive task that measures working memory capacity and cognitive control. The task requires participants to monitor a series of stimuli (usually visual or auditory) and indicate whether the current stimulus matches the stimulus presented n items back in the series. For example, in a 2-back task, participants would be presented with a sequence of letters or numbers and would have to indicate whether the current letter or number matches the one presented two items back in the sequence. In a 3-back task, participants would have to match the current stimulus to the one presented three items back, and so on. The n-back task is a relatively simple task that can be easily administered and scored, making it a popular tool in cognitive research. The task is also sensitive to individual differences in working memory capacity and cognitive control, and has been used in studies investigating various cognitive disorders such as schizophrenia, depression, and ADHD. The n-back task can be adapted to different modalities, such as auditory and visual, and can also be modified by changing the value of n to vary the level of difficulty. A more difficult n-back task, such as a 3-back or 4-back task, requires greater working memory capacity and cognitive control to perform accurately, while an easier task such as a 1-back task would be less demanding.</p>
			<p><strong>Source:</strong> Kirchner, W. K. (1958). Age differences in short-term retention of rapidly changing information. Journal of Experimental Psychology, 55(4), 352–358. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0043688" target='_blank'>10.1037/h0043688</a></p>
			<p><strong>Link</strong> <a href='https://www.millisecond.com/download/library/nback' target='_blank'>N-Back Task Online</a>, <a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/N-back' target='_blank'>Wikipedia</a></p> 
		</method>
		
		<method id="tct" category="summative,empirical,quantitative,objective,performance" title="Quantitative Objective Performance: Task Completion Time (TCT)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>In the context of human-computer interaction (HCI), task completion time (TCT) refers to the amount of time it takes for a user to complete a specific task or set of tasks using an interface or system. TCT is an important usability metric that can be used to evaluate the efficiency and effectiveness of an interface design, as well as to compare different interface designs. TCT can be measured in a variety of ways, depending on the specific task and interface being evaluated. For example, TCT for a simple task like filling out a form might be measured as the time it takes for a user to complete all required fields and submit the form. For a more complex task like creating a digital illustration, TCT might be measured as the time it takes for a user to complete all steps in the process, from initial sketching to final rendering. In addition to providing insight into the overall efficiency of an interface design, TCT can also help identify specific areas where users may encounter difficulties or confusion during a task. By tracking TCT and analyzing any patterns or trends that emerge, designers and researchers can make informed decisions about how to improve interface designs and optimize task performance.</p>
			<p><strong>Link:</strong> <a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_to_completion' target='_blank'>Wikipedia</a></p> 
		</method>
		
		<method id="iat" category="summative,empirical,quantitative,objective,biases" title="Quantitative Objective Bias: Implicit Association Test (IAT)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Implicit Association Test (IAT) is a psychological tool that measures implicit biases or attitudes towards certain social groups, concepts, or topics. The test was first developed by social psychologists Anthony Greenwald, Debbie McGhee, and Jordan Schwartz in the 1990s. The IAT measures the strength of automatic associations between mental representations of certain social groups, concepts, or topics and evaluations (e.g., positive or negative). The test involves a computer-based task in which participants categorize stimuli (e.g., words or images) into one of two categories as quickly as possible. For example, participants might categorize words as "good" or "bad" and images of different social groups (e.g., white and black faces) as belonging to one of two categories (e.g., "American" or "foreign"). The IAT measures the relative speed with which participants categorize stimuli when the categories are paired in different ways, providing an indirect measure of implicit biases or attitudes towards the categories being tested. If participants are faster to categorize "good" words with "white" faces and "bad" words with "black" faces than the reverse, this suggests an implicit bias towards white faces and against black faces. The IAT has been used in research to study various topics, including racial bias, gender bias, and attitudes towards different social groups. The IAT has been criticized for its reliance on a single task to measure implicit attitudes, and some researchers have called for more diverse measures of implicit attitudes. Despite these criticisms, the IAT remains a widely used and influential tool in social psychology research.</p>
			<p><strong>Source:</strong> Nosek, B. A., Greenwald, A. G., Banaji, M. R. (2005). Understanding and using the Implicit Association Test: II. Method variables and construct validity. Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin. 31 (2): 166–180. DOI: <a href="https://doi.org/10.1177/0146167204271418" target='_blank'>10.1177/0146167204271418</a></p>
			<p><strong>Link</strong> <a href='https://implicit.harvard.edu/implicit/selectatouchtest.html' target='_blank'>IAT Testing Online</a>, <a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Implicit-association_test' target='_blank'>Wikipedia</a></p> 
		</method>
		
		<method id="cysesh" category="summative,empirical,quantitative,subjective,selfefficacy" title="Quantitative Subjective Self-Efficacy: Cybersecurity Self-Efficacy in Smart Homes (CySESH) Scale">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Cybersecurity Self-Efficacy in Smart Homes (CySESH) scale is a 12-item unidimensional measure of domain-specific self-efficacy beliefs. CySESH showed the expected relationship trends with other established psychological traits (i.e., self-efficacy in information security, outcome expectation, self-esteem, and optimism), which confirmed its distinctness. By following state-of-the-art test construction and open science processes, the scale provides researchers and practitioners with a meaningful evaluation tool.</p>
			<p><strong>Source:</strong> Nele Borgert, Oliver D. Reithmaier, Luisa Jansen, Larina Hillemann, Ian Hussey, and Malte Elson. 2023. Home Is Where the Smart Is: Development and Validation of the Cybersecurity Self-Efficacy in Smart Homes (CySESH) Scale. In Proceedings of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI '23). Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA, Article 507, 1–15. DOI: <a href="https://doi.org/10.1145/3544548.3580860" target='_blank'>10.1145/3544548.3580860 </a></p> 
		</method>

		<method id="mecue" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,userexperience" title="Quantitative Subjective User Experience: meCUE Questionnaire (2.0)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The meCUE 2.0 is a modular self-report questionnaire for evaluating user experience. It covers instrumental product perceptions, non-instrumental perceptions, emotions, consequences of use, and an overall evaluation. It is suitable when researchers want a broader UX assessment beyond classical usability-only instruments.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Minge, M., and Thüring, M. (2018). The MeCUE Questionnaire (2.0): Meeting Five Basic Requirements for Lean and Standardized UX Assessment. In Proceedings of the Mensch und Computer 2018 Conference. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-91797-9_33">10.1007/978-3-319-91797-9_33</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="ues" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,userexperience" title="Quantitative Subjective User Experience: User Engagement Scale (UES)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The User Engagement Scale measures the degree to which users are focused, involved, and absorbed during interaction. It is useful when engagement should be distinguished from general usability or overall satisfaction.</p>
			<p><strong>Source (Original Concept): </strong>O'Brien, H. L., and Toms, E. G. (2010). The development and evaluation of a survey to measure user engagement. Journal of the American Society for Information Science and Technology, 61(1), 50-69. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1002/asi.21229">10.1002/asi.21229</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="sam" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,emotions" title="Quantitative Subjective Emotions: Self-Assessment Manikin (SAM)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Self-Assessment Manikin (SAM) is a non-verbal pictorial instrument for measuring affective responses on the dimensions valence, arousal, and dominance. It is especially useful when a compact and language-light emotion measure is needed.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Bradley, M. M., and Lang, P. J. (1994). Measuring emotion: The self-assessment manikin and the semantic differential. Journal of Behavior Therapy and Experimental Psychiatry, 25(1), 49-59. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1016/0005-7916(94)90063-9">10.1016/0005-7916(94)90063-9</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="fss" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,flow" title="Quantitative Subjective Flow: Flow State Scale (FSS)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Flow State Scale (FSS) is a self-report measure for assessing the subjective experience of flow during an activity. It captures aspects such as concentration, sense of control, merging of action and awareness, autotelic experience, and intrinsic enjoyment. In HCI, it is useful for studying highly engaging interactions such as games, creative tools, immersive environments, and performance-oriented interfaces.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Jackson, S. A., and Marsh, H. W. (1996). Development and validation of a scale to measure optimal experience: The Flow State Scale. Journal of Sport and Exercise Psychology, 18(1), 17-35. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1123/jsep.18.1.17">10.1123/jsep.18.1.17</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="ssq" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,health" title="Quantitative Subjective Health: Simulator Sickness Questionnaire (SSQ)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Simulator Sickness Questionnaire is one of the standard self-report measures for symptoms such as nausea, oculomotor discomfort, and disorientation after simulator or virtual environment exposure. It is widely used in VR and XR studies to assess cybersickness-related symptoms.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Kennedy, R. S., Lane, N. E., Berbaum, K. S., and Lilienthal, M. G. (1993). Simulator Sickness Questionnaire: An Enhanced Method for Quantifying Simulator Sickness. The International Journal of Aviation Psychology, 3(3), 203-220. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1207/s15327108ijap0303_3">10.1207/s15327108ijap0303_3</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="vrsq" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,health" title="Quantitative Subjective Health: Virtual Reality Sickness Questionnaire (VRSQ)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Virtual Reality Sickness Questionnaire is a VR-focused self-report instrument for assessing sickness symptoms in head-mounted display environments. It is often used as a more targeted alternative to the SSQ in modern VR studies.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Kim, H. K., Park, J., Choi, Y., and Choe, M. (2018). Virtual reality sickness questionnaire (VRSQ): Motion sickness measurement index in a virtual reality environment. Applied Ergonomics, 69, 66-73. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apergo.2017.12.016">10.1016/j.apergo.2017.12.016</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="godspeed" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,humanlikeness" title="Quantitative Subjective Human-Likeness: Godspeed Questionnaire Series">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Godspeed Questionnaire Series is widely used in HRI to assess perceptions of robots and artificial agents. It contains scales for anthropomorphism, animacy, likeability, perceived intelligence, and perceived safety, and is suitable for studies comparing robot or agent designs.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Bartneck, C., Kulić, D., Croft, E., and Zoghbi, S. (2009). Measurement Instruments for the Anthropomorphism, Animacy, Likeability, Perceived Intelligence, and Perceived Safety of Robots. International Journal of Social Robotics, 1, 71-81. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s12369-008-0001-3">10.1007/s12369-008-0001-3</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="rosas" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,socialacceptance" title="Quantitative Subjective Social Acceptance: Robotic Social Attributes Scale (RoSAS)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Robotic Social Attributes Scale measures social perceptions of robots across dimensions such as warmth, competence, and discomfort. It is useful when evaluating how acceptable or socially appropriate a robot appears to users.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Carpinella, C. M., Wyman, A. B., Perez, M. A., and Stroessner, S. J. (2017). The Robotic Social Attributes Scale (RoSAS): Development and Validation. In Proceedings of the 2017 ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1145/2909824.3020208">10.1145/2909824.3020208</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="tia" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,trust" title="Quantitative Subjective Trust: Trust in Automation Questionnaire (TiA)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Trust in Automation Questionnaire is used to assess a person's trust in automated systems. It is relevant for HCI studies involving intelligent systems, decision support, assistance, or semi-autonomous technologies.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Körber, M. (2018). Theoretical Considerations and Development of a Questionnaire to Measure Trust in Automation. In Proceedings of the 20th Congress of the International Ergonomics Association (IEA 2018). DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-96074-6_2">10.1007/978-3-319-96074-6_2</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="almere" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,socialacceptance" title="Quantitative Subjective Social Acceptance: Almere Model Questionnaire">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Almere Model Questionnaire is an acceptance instrument for assistive social agents and robots. It extends technology acceptance ideas to socially interactive systems and is especially useful in HRI and assistive technology contexts.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Heerink, M., Kröse, B., Evers, V., and Wielinga, B. (2010). Assessing Acceptance of Assistive Social Agent Technology by Older Adults: the Almere Model. International Journal of Social Robotics, 2, 361-375. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s12369-010-0068-5">10.1007/s12369-010-0068-5</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="iuipc" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,socialacceptance" title="Quantitative Subjective Social Acceptance: Internet Users' Information Privacy Concerns (IUIPC)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The IUIPC scale measures concerns about the collection, control, and awareness of personal information online. It is useful in HCI when privacy perceptions are important for understanding acceptance, trust, or adoption of digital systems.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Malhotra, N. K., Kim, S. S., and Agarwal, J. (2004). Internet Users' Information Privacy Concerns (IUIPC): The Construct, the Scale, and a Causal Model. Information Systems Research, 15(4), 336-355. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1287/isre.1040.0032">10.1287/isre.1040.0032</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="visawis" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,userexperience" title="Quantitative Subjective User Experience: Visual Aesthetics of Websites Inventory - Short Version (VisAWI-S)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The VisAWI-S is a short questionnaire for measuring perceived visual aesthetics of websites and related interfaces. It is useful when visual design quality should be assessed separately from usability or general user experience.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Moshagen, M., and Thielsch, M. T. (2013). A short version of the visual aesthetics of websites inventory. Behaviour and Information Technology, 32(12), 1305-1311. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1080/0144929X.2012.694910">10.1080/0144929X.2012.694910</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="experienceprototyping" category="formative,solutions,prototype" title="Prototyping Method: Experience Prototyping">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Experience prototyping is a design method that enables designers, researchers, and stakeholders to actively explore and communicate experiences with a future product or service. It is especially useful for interactive, embodied, ubicomp, or XR concepts where static mockups are insufficient.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Buchenau, M., and Suri, J. F. (2000). Experience Prototyping. In Proceedings of the 3rd Conference on Designing Interactive Systems (DIS '00), 424-433. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1145/347642.347802">10.1145/347642.347802</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="wizardofoz" category="formative,solutions,prototype" title="Prototyping Method: Wizard of Oz (WoZ)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Wizard of Oz is a prototyping method in which participants interact with a system that appears autonomous but is partially or fully operated by a hidden human. It is useful for evaluating concepts and interaction flows before the underlying technology has been fully implemented.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Riek, L. D. (2012). Wizard of Oz Studies in HRI: A Systematic Review and New Reporting Guidelines. Journal of Human-Robot Interaction, 1(1), 119-136. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.5898/JHRI.1.1.Riek">10.5898/JHRI.1.1.Riek</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="constructiveinteraction" category="empirical,qualitative,subjective,randomsample" title="Qualitative Feedback: Constructive Interaction / Co-Discovery Learning">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Constructive interaction is a usability evaluation method in which two participants work together on tasks and naturally verbalize their thoughts while interacting. It is often used as an alternative to think-aloud, especially when a more natural conversational style is desired.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>van den Haak, M. J., de Jong, M. D. T., and Schellens, P. J. (2004). Employing think-aloud protocols and constructive interaction to test the usability of online library catalogues: a methodological comparison. Interacting with Computers, 16(6), 1153-1170. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.intcom.2004.07.007">10.1016/j.intcom.2004.07.007</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="suspresence" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,presence" title="Quantitative Subjective Presence: Slater-Usoh-Steed Presence Questionnaire (SUS Presence)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Slater-Usoh-Steed questionnaire is a classic self-report measure of presence in virtual environments. It is commonly used in VR research when a short and established presence instrument is needed.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Slater, M., Usoh, M., and Steed, A. (1994). Depth of Presence in Virtual Environments. Presence: Teleoperators and Virtual Environments, 3(2), 130-144. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1162/pres.1994.3.2.130">10.1162/pres.1994.3.2.130</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="uessf" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,userexperience" title="Quantitative Subjective User Experience: User Engagement Scale Short Form (UES-SF)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The User Engagement Scale Short Form (UES-SF) is a shortened version of the original UES for efficient use in studies where questionnaire space is limited. It provides a compact assessment of user engagement while preserving the core dimensions of the original measure. It is especially useful in HCI evaluations that combine several questionnaires in a single study.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>O'Brien, H. L., Cairns, P., and Hall, M. (2018). A practical approach to measuring user engagement with the refined user engagement scale (UES) and new UES short form. International Journal of Human-Computer Studies, 112, 28-39. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhcs.2018.01.004">10.1016/j.ijhcs.2018.01.004</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="trustinautomation" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,trust" title="Quantitative Subjective Trust: Trust in Automation Scale">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Trust in Automation Scale is a self-report measure developed to assess the extent to which users trust an automated system. It captures perceptions such as reliability, predictability, dependability, and confidence in automated behavior. In HCI and human-AI interaction, the scale is useful when evaluating whether users appropriately trust or distrust automated support, decision systems, or intelligent interfaces.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Jian, J.-Y., Bisantz, A. M., and Drury, C. G. (2000). Foundations for an empirically determined scale of trust in automated systems. International Journal of Cognitive Ergonomics, 4(1), 53-71. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1207/S15327566IJCE0401_04">10.1207/S15327566IJCE0401_04</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="scs" category="empirical,quantitative,subjective,explainability" title="Quantitative Subjective Explainability: System Causability Scale (SCS)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The System Causability Scale (SCS) is a questionnaire for evaluating the quality of explanations provided by intelligent systems. It focuses on whether an explanation helps users understand causal relations, supports effective reasoning, and is usable in context. The scale is particularly relevant in HCI research on explainable AI, decision support, and human-AI interaction.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Holzinger, A., Carrington, A., and Müller, H. (2020). Measuring the quality of explanations: The System Causability Scale (SCS). KI - Künstliche Intelligenz, 34, 193-198. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s13218-020-00636-z">10.1007/s13218-020-00636-z</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="samba" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,accessibility" title="Quantitative Objective Accessibility: SAMBA (Semi-Automatic Method for Measuring Barriers of Accessibility)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>SAMBA is a semi-automatic accessibility evaluation method for identifying and quantifying barriers in web interfaces. It combines automated inspection with expert judgment and focuses on the severity and impact of accessibility barriers rather than only reporting rule violations. In HCI, it is useful when researchers want a more structured objective accessibility assessment than a simple pass/fail conformance check.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Brajnik, G., and Lomuscio, R. (2007). SAMBA: a semi-automatic method for measuring barriers of accessibility. In Proceedings of the 9th International ACM SIGACCESS Conference on Computers and Accessibility (ASSETS '07). DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1145/1296843.1296853">10.1145/1296843.1296853</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="wcagconformanceaudit" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,accessibility" title="Quantitative Objective Accessibility: WCAG Conformance Audit / WCAG-Based Accessibility Evaluation">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>A WCAG-based accessibility audit evaluates whether an interface conforms to the Web Content Accessibility Guidelines and is one of the most common objective accessibility methods in HCI and web research. It is especially useful when researchers need a structured expert review of accessibility requirements and want to document conformance, violations, and reliability of judgments in a standardized way.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Brajnik, G., Yesilada, Y., and Harper, S. (2012). Is accessibility conformance an elusive property? A study of validity and reliability of WCAG 2.0. ACM Transactions on Accessible Computing, 4(2), Article 8. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1145/2141943.2141946">10.1145/2141943.2141946</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="teamusabilitytesting" category="empirical,qualitative,subjective,collaboration,randomsample" title="Qualitative Feedback: Team Usability Testing">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Team Usability Testing is a groupware evaluation method for real-time distributed collaboration systems. Unlike individual usability testing, it is designed to uncover team-level usability problems that only occur when several users work together on a shared task. The method combines questionnaires, on-screen behavior recordings, and post-experiment interviews, and is especially useful for CSCW and collaborative software.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Geszten, D., Tóvölgyi, S., and Hercegfi, K. (2021). Empirical study of Team Usability Testing: a laboratory experiment. Cognition, Technology &amp; Work, 23, 575-594. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10111-020-00647-8">10.1007/s10111-020-00647-8</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="mechanicsofcollaboration" category="formative,analytical,datadriven,collaboration" title="Data-driven Analysis: Mechanics of Collaboration (MoC) Task Analysis">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Mechanics of Collaboration is a task-analytic framework for modeling collaborative actions in shared-workspace groupware. It helps researchers analyze what users need to do together, where collaborative breakdowns occur, and which aspects of a system hinder coordination. In HCI, it is particularly useful for the evaluation and redesign of CSCW tools and synchronous collaboration systems.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Pinelle, D., Gutwin, C., and Greenberg, S. (2003). Task analysis for groupware usability evaluation: Modeling shared-workspace tasks with the mechanics of collaboration. ACM Transactions on Computer-Human Interaction, 10(4), 281-311. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1145/966930.966932">10.1145/966930.966932</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="sagat" category="empirical,quantitative,objective,awareness" title="Quantitative Objective Awareness: Situation Awareness Global Assessment Technique (SAGAT)">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The Situation Awareness Global Assessment Technique (SAGAT) is an objective method for measuring situation awareness in dynamic tasks. It typically pauses an ongoing simulation or interactive task and probes the participant's knowledge of the current state, thereby assessing perception, comprehension, and projection. In HCI, SAGAT is relevant for complex interactive systems such as driving, aviation, supervision, XR, and safety-critical interfaces.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Endsley, M. R. (1988). Situation awareness global assessment technique (SAGAT). In Proceedings of the IEEE 1988 National Aerospace and Electronics Conference, 789-795. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1109/NAECON.1988.195097">10.1109/NAECON.1988.195097</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="workspaceawareness" category="analytical,datadriven,awareness" title="Data-driven Analysis: Workspace Awareness Framework">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Workspace awareness refers to the up-to-the-moment understanding of another person's interaction with a shared workspace. The Workspace Awareness Framework provides a structured way to analyze the information people need to coordinate their actions in collaborative systems, such as who is present, where they are working, and what they are doing. In HCI, it is useful for analyzing and designing real-time groupware and collaborative interfaces.</p>
			<p><strong>Source: </strong>Gutwin, C., and Greenberg, S. (2002). A Descriptive Framework of Workspace Awareness for Real-Time Groupware. Computer Supported Cooperative Work, 11, 411-446. DOI: <a target="_blank" href="https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1021271517844">10.1023/A:1021271517844</a></p>
		</method>

		<method id="criticalreview" category="literature,narrative" title="A Critical Literature Review">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Aims to demonstrate writer has extensively researched literature and critically evaluated its quality. Goes beyond mere description to include degree of analysis and conceptual innovation. Typically results in hypothesis or model. Seeks to identify significant items in the field.</p>
			<ul>
				<li><strong>Review Guidelines: </strong><a href='https://instr.iastate.libguides.com/c.php?g=885773' target='_blank'>Click here</a></li>
				<li><strong>Review Time: </strong>Up to author</li><li><strong>Review Resources: </strong>Up to author</li>
				<li><strong>Team: </strong>One author</li><li><strong>Searching strategy: </strong>Any or none</li>
				<li><strong>Appraisal: </strong>No formal quality assessment. Attempts to evaluate according to contribution.</li><li><strong>Results synthesis: </strong>Typically narrative, perhaps conceptual or chronological.</li>
				<li><strong>Analysis: </strong>Significant component: seeks to identify conceptual contribution to embody existing or derive new theory.</li>
			</ul>
			Grant, M.J. and Booth, A. (2009).  <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/epdf/10.1111/j.1471-1842.2009.00848.x" target='_blank'>A typology of reviews: An analysis of 14 review types and associated methodologies.</a> Health Information and Libraries Journal, 26(2), 91-108.
		</method>

		<method id="rapidreview" category="literature,narrative" title="A Rapid Literature Review">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Assessment of what is already known about a policy or practice issue, by using systematic review methods to search and critically appraise existing research.</p>
			<ul>
				<li><strong>Review Guidelines: </strong><a href='https://instr.iastate.libguides.com/c.php?g=885773' target='_blank'>Click here</a></li>
				<li><strong>Review Time: </strong>2 - 6 months</li><li><strong>Review Resources: </strong>Up to author</li>
				<li><strong>Team: </strong>One author</li><li><strong>Searching strategy: </strong>Any or none</li>
				<li><strong>Appraisal: </strong>Time-limited. Attempts to evaluate according to contribution.</li><li><strong>Results synthesis: </strong>Typically narrative and tabular.</li>
				<li><strong>Analysis: </strong>Quantities of literature and overall quality/direction of effect of literature.</li>
			</ul>
			Grant, M.J. and Booth, A. (2009).  <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/epdf/10.1111/j.1471-1842.2009.00848.x" target='_blank'>A typology of reviews: An analysis of 14 review types and associated methodologies.</a> Health Information and Libraries Journal, 26(2), 91-108.
		</method>

		<method id="stateoftheartreview" category="literature,narrative" title="A State-of-the-Art Literature Review">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Tend to address more current matters in contrast to other combined retrospective and current approaches. May offer new perspectives on issue or point out area for further research. Aims for comprehensive searching of current literature.</p>
			<ul>
				<li><strong>Review Guidelines: </strong><a href='https://instr.iastate.libguides.com/c.php?g=885773' target='_blank'>Click here</a></li>
				<li><strong>Review Time: </strong>Up to author</li><li><strong>Review Resources: </strong>Up to author</li>
				<li><strong>Team: </strong>One author</li><li><strong>Searching strategy: </strong>Any or none</li>
				<li><strong>Appraisal: </strong>No formal quality assessment.</li><li><strong>Results synthesis: </strong>Typically narrative, may have tabular accompaniment.</li>
				<li><strong>Analysis: </strong>Current state of knowledge and priorities for future investigation and research.</li>
			</ul>
			Grant, M.J. and Booth, A. (2009).  <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/epdf/10.1111/j.1471-1842.2009.00848.x" target='_blank'>A typology of reviews: An analysis of 14 review types and associated methodologies.</a> Health Information and Libraries Journal, 26(2), 91-108.
		</method>

		<method id="narrativereview" category="literature,narrative" title="A Narrative Literature Review">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Traditional (narrative) literature reviews provide a broad overview of a research topic with <strong>no clear methodological approach</strong>. Information is collected and interpreted unsystematically with subjective summaries of findings. Authors aim to describe and discuss the literature from a contextual or theoretical point of view. Although the reviews may be conducted by topic experts, due to preconceived ideas or conclusions, they could be subject to bias. This sort of literature review can be appropriate if you have a broad topic area, are working on your own, or have time constraints.</p>
			<ul>
				<li><strong>Review Guidelines: </strong><a href='https://journal.emwa.org/writing-for-lay-audiences/writing-narrative-style-literature-reviews/' target='_blank'>Click here</a></li>
				<li><strong>Review Time: </strong>1 - 4 weeks</li><li><strong>Review Resources: </strong>Up to author</li>
				<li><strong>Team: </strong>One or more authors</li><li><strong>Searching strategy: </strong>Any or none</li>
				<li><strong>Appraisal: </strong>Any or none</li><li><strong>Results synthesis: </strong>Narrative commentary</li>
				<li><strong>Analysis: </strong>Summary of selected articles</li>
			</ul>
			Ferrari R. <a href='https://journal.emwa.org/writing-for-lay-audiences/writing-narrative-style-literature-reviews/' target='_blank'>Writing narrative style literature reviews</a>. Medical Writing. 2015 Dec 1;24(4):230-5.

			Grant, M.J. and Booth, A. (2009).  <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/epdf/10.1111/j.1471-1842.2009.00848.x" target='_blank'>A typology of reviews: An analysis of 14 review types and associated methodologies.</a> Health Information and Libraries Journal, 26(2), 91-108.
		</method>

		<method id="systematicreviewPRISMA" category="literature,systematic" title="A Systematic Literature Review: PRISMA Method">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>PRISMA is an evidence-based minimum set of items for reporting in systematic reviews and meta-analyses. PRISMA primarily focuses on the reporting of reviews evaluating the effects of interventions, but can also be used as a basis for reporting systematic reviews with objectives other than evaluating interventions.</p>
			<ul>
				<li><strong>Review Guidelines: </strong><a href='https://prisma-statement.org/Default.aspx' target='_blank'>Click here</a></li>
				<li><strong>Review Time: </strong>4-6 weeks or more depending on: number of databases, complexity, number of papers</li>
				<li><strong>Review Resources: </strong>Appropriate research databases for the research question</li>
				<li><strong>Team: </strong>Two or more people required for screening</li>
				<li><strong>Searching strategy: </strong>Exhaustive - aiming for all data published</li>
				<li><strong>Appraisal: </strong>Quality assessment involved</li>
				<li><strong>Results synthesis: </strong>Typically narrative or tabular</li>
				<li><strong>Analysis: </strong>what is known; recommendations for practice; what remains unknown; uncertainty around findings; recommendations for future research; taxonomies; classification schemes; methodological overview; ...</li>
			</ul>
			<a href='https://prisma-statement.org/PRISMAStatement/CitingAndUsingPRISMA' target='_blank'>PRISMA Statement and Citing PRISMA</a>
			Grant, M.J. and Booth, A. (2009).  <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/epdf/10.1111/j.1471-1842.2009.00848.x" target='_blank'>A typology of reviews: An analysis of 14 review types and associated methodologies.</a> Health Information and Libraries Journal, 26(2), 91-108.
		</method>

		<method id="systematicreviewKitchenham" category="literature,systematic" title="A Systematic Literature Review: Kitchenham Procedure">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Appropriate for software engineering researchers and a mean of evaluating and interpreting all available research relevant to a particular research question, topic area, or phenomenon of interest. Aim is to present a fair evaluation of a research topic by using a trustworthy, rigorous, and auditable methodology. The guideline presented was derived from three existing guidelines used by medical researchers. The guideline has been adapted to reflect the specific problems of software engineering research. The guideline covers three phases of a systematic review: (1) planning the review, (2) conducting the review and (3) reporting the review. It does not consider the impact of question type on the review procedures, nor does it specify in detail mechanisms needed to undertake meta-analysis.</p>
			<ul>
				<li><strong>Review Guidelines: </strong><a href='https://www.inf.ufsc.br/~aldo.vw/kitchenham.pdf' target='_blank'>Click here</a></li>
				<li><strong>Review Time: </strong>4-6 weeks or more depending on: number of databases, complexity, number of papers</li>
				<li><strong>Review Resources: </strong>Appropriate research databases for the research question</li>
				<li><strong>Team: </strong>Two or more people required for screening</li>
				<li><strong>Searching strategy: </strong>Exhaustive - aiming for all data published</li>
				<li><strong>Appraisal: </strong>Quality assessment involved</li>
				<li><strong>Results synthesis: </strong>Typically narrative or tabular</li>
				<li><strong>Analysis: </strong>what is known; recommendations for practice; what remains unknown; uncertainty around findings; recommendations for future research; taxonomies; classification schemes; methodological overview; ...</li>
			</ul>
			Kitchenham, B. (2004). <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Barbara-Kitchenham/publication/228756057_Procedures_for_Performing_Systematic_Reviews/links/618cfae961f09877207f8471/Procedures-for-Performing-Systematic-Reviews.pdf">Procedures for performing systematic reviews</a>. Keele, UK, Keele University, 33(2004), 1-26.
			Grant, M.J. and Booth, A. (2009).  <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/epdf/10.1111/j.1471-1842.2009.00848.x" target='_blank'>A typology of reviews: An analysis of 14 review types and associated methodologies.</a> Health Information and Libraries Journal, 26(2), 91-108.
		</method>

		<method id="systematicreviewAPISSER" category="literature,systematic" title="A Systematic Literature Review: The APISSER Methodology">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>Based on the well-known and proven PRISMA methodology from medical sciences, APISSER adapts and enhances the method to follow a task-oriented engineering flow and to be supported by customized tools. APISSER takes a step forward towards standardizing the methodology for executing systematic literature reviews in engineering by proposing a tool-supported and task-oriented engineering flow methodology to execute systematic literature reviews in engineering.</p>
			<ul>
				<li><strong>Review Guidelines: </strong><a href='https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/ielx7/6287639/9668973/09698182.pdf' target='_blank'>Click here</a></li>
				<li><strong>Review Time: </strong>4-6 weeks or more depending on: number of databases, complexity, number of papers</li>
				<li><strong>Review Resources: </strong>Appropriate research databases for the research question</li>
				<li><strong>Team: </strong>One or (better) two people required for screening</li>
				<li><strong>Searching strategy: </strong>Completeness of searching determined by scope constraints, often broad, often iterative</li>
				<li><strong>Appraisal: </strong>No formal quality assessment</li>
				<li><strong>Results synthesis: </strong>Typically tabular with some narrative commentary</li>
				<li><strong>Analysis: </strong>Characterizes quantity and breadth of literature. Attempts to specify the viability of more focused reviews</li>
			</ul>
			Castillo, S., and Grbovic, P. (2022).  IEEE Access, 10, 23700-23707. <a href='https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/ielx7/6287639/9668973/09698182.pdf' target='_blank'>The APISSER Methodology for Systematic Literature Reviews in Engineering</a>, 13(3), 141-146.
			Grant, M.J. and Booth, A. (2009).  <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/epdf/10.1111/j.1471-1842.2009.00848.x" target='_blank'>A typology of reviews: An analysis of 14 review types and associated methodologies.</a> Health Information and Libraries Journal, 26(2), 91-108.
		</method>

		<method id="scopingreviewJBI" category="literature,scoping" title="A Scoping Review: The JBI Method">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>The JBI guidance for scoping reviews includes additional guidance on several methodological issues, such as when a scoping review is (or is not) appropriate, and how to extract, analyze, and present results, and provides clarification for implications for practice and research. Furthermore, it is aligned with the PRISMA-ScR to ensure consistent reporting.</p>
			<ul>
				<li><strong>Review Guidelines: </strong><a href='https://rgu-repository.worktribe.com/preview/998095/PETERS%202020%20Updated%20methodological.pdf' target='_blank'>Click here</a></li>
				<li><strong>Review Time: </strong>4-6 weeks or more depending on: number of databases, complexity, number of papers</li>
				<li><strong>Review Resources: </strong>Appropriate research databases for the research question</li>
				<li><strong>Team: </strong>One or (better) two people required for screening</li>
				<li><strong>Searching strategy: </strong>Completeness of searching determined by scope constraints, often broad, often iterative</li>
				<li><strong>Appraisal: </strong>No formal quality assessment</li>
				<li><strong>Results synthesis: </strong>Typically tabular with some narrative commentary</li>
				<li><strong>Analysis: </strong>Characterizes quantity and breadth of literature. Attempts to specify the viability of more focused reviews</li>
			</ul>
			<a href='https://rgu-repository.worktribe.com/preview/998095/PETERS%202020%20Updated%20methodological.pdf' target='_blank'>JBI Review Guide</a>
			Grant, M.J. and Booth, A. (2009).  <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/epdf/10.1111/j.1471-1842.2009.00848.x" target='_blank'>A typology of reviews: An analysis of 14 review types and associated methodologies.</a> Health Information and Libraries Journal, 26(2), 91-108.
		</method>

		<method id="scopingreviewPRISMASc" category="literature,scoping" title="A Scoping Review: The PRISMA-Sc Method">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>PRISMA-SC is a PRISMA extension for scoping reviews. The checklist contains 20 essential reporting items and 2 optional items to include when completing a scoping review. Scoping reviews serve to synthesize evidence and assess the scope of literature on a topic. Among other objectives, scoping reviews help determine whether a systematic review of the literature is warranted.</p>
			<ul>
				<li><strong>Review Guidelines: </strong><a href='https://journals.lww.com/ijebh/fulltext/2015/09000/guidance_for_conducting_systematic_scoping_reviews.5.aspx' target='_blank'>Click here</a></li>
				<li><strong>Review Time: </strong>4-6 weeks or more depending on: number of databases, complexity, number of papers</li>
				<li><strong>Review Resources: </strong>Appropriate research databases for the research question</li>
				<li><strong>Team: </strong>One or (better) two people required for screening</li>
				<li><strong>Searching strategy: </strong>Completeness of searching determined by scope constraints, often broad, often iterative</li>
				<li><strong>Appraisal: </strong>No formal quality assessment</li>
				<li><strong>Results synthesis: </strong>Typically tabular with some narrative commentary</li>
				<li><strong>Analysis: </strong>Characterizes quantity and breadth of literature. Attempts to specify the viability of more focused reviews</li>
			</ul>
			<a href='https://prisma-statement.org/PRISMAStatement/CitingAndUsingPRISMA' target='_blank'>PRISMA Statement and Citing PRISMA</a>
			Grant, M.J. and Booth, A. (2009).  <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/epdf/10.1111/j.1471-1842.2009.00848.x" target='_blank'>A typology of reviews: An analysis of 14 review types and associated methodologies.</a> Health Information and Libraries Journal, 26(2), 91-108.
		</method>

		<method id="metareviewPRISMASc" category="literature,metaanalysis" title= "A Meta-Analysis: The PRISMA Method">
			<p><strong>Description: </strong>PRISMA is an evidence-based minimum set of items for reporting in systematic reviews and meta-analyses. PRISMA primarily focuses on the reporting of reviews evaluating the effects of interventions, but can also be used as a basis for reporting systematic reviews with objectives other than evaluating interventions.</p>
			<ul>
				<li><strong>Review Guidelines: </strong><a href='https://prisma-statement.org/Default.aspx' target='_blank'>Click here</a></li>
				<li><strong>Review Time: </strong>4-6 weeks or more depending on: number of databases, complexity, number of papers</li>
				<li><strong>Review Resources: </strong>Appropriate research databases for the research question</li>
				<li><strong>Team: </strong>Two or more people required for screening</li>
				<li><strong>Searching strategy: </strong>Exhaustive - aiming for all data published</li>
				<li><strong>Appraisal: </strong>Quality assessment involved</li>
				<li><strong>Results synthesis: </strong>Typically narrative or tabular</li>
				<li><strong>Analysis: </strong>what is known; recommendations for practice; what remains unknown; uncertainty around findings; recommendations for future research; taxonomies; classification schemes; methodological overview; ...</li>
			</ul>
			<a href='https://prisma-statement.org/PRISMAStatement/CitingAndUsingPRISMA' target='_blank'>PRISMA Statement and Citing PRISMA</a>
			Grant, M.J. and Booth, A. (2009).  <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/epdf/10.1111/j.1471-1842.2009.00848.x" target='_blank'>A typology of reviews: An analysis of 14 review types and associated methodologies.</a> Health Information and Libraries Journal, 26(2), 91-108.
		</method>
	</measures>
</research>
